Heat. Heat.
Hey,
hey, hey.
Heat.
Hello everybody. Good evening, good day
and welcome back to the ask a bajid
show. I hope you are all doing great
this fine evening or fine day wherever
you are. Let's see who is there on the
live chat with us. Let us see I can see
Naganand Shinoi good evening. M AK4 G1U.
Avin Random Skull. Hello. Surya Pratab
here is here from Tenjiku. Very nice.
Tenjiku. Uh Geopolitical Dubai is here
from Indor. Shik Rayan. I do remember
you sir. I've seen you before. Uh Devil
F9N.
Uh Tanesh Pandy. Hello. Chaitana Manuja.
Uh V shon.
All right. Anka G is here. Good evening
ma'am. Devil is also here. Um, who else?
Swami is here. Chat DSP. Namaste.
Nabarita Das. Namaste. G. Basar bandit.
Hello. Namaskarum. Uh, Adwit Ashwani
written by Deb. De Pratt. Dana. Namaste.
Written by De J. Jagnath. I suppose.
Zalinsky will win is here. Is from
Nepal. Good to have you sir. From Nepal.
Uh, Daran Rajendra Datar. Who else do we
have? The Baron Zemo Niraj Bardage
Tushar Kaluri Hello Priyanka Javalia is
here from Gorgon. Good evening ma'am.
Adwit is here. Sai Nirup Namaskar
Yuk 80045 hello. Uh Swami says have I
watched 2001 a space odyssey? I'm not
sure if I've watched it but I have read
it. Um Rahul Dunak hello
uh Bush Runner Ultimate Power A1. Yo
Krishna of the Surinabies Netherlands is
here. Hello good to see you sir. Manisha
Kardos namaste namaste.
Um who else? Sumit Agaral. Hola kennel
4605 sar s.
Um who else? Who else? Um real brother
Vladimir Putin once again I who else?
Khan. Kahan is here. Journey with
Karthik
Anandam S2825 Chatany once again uh No
Club Namaste
uh and everybody else. Okay, so uh let
us Crazy Brain is here. Good to see you
crazy brain journey with Karthik once
again. Ultimate Power is here. I haven't
seen Dark on Netflix but maybe I shall
see in the future if I get some time to
to watch stuff. Uh Northern Roshan is
here. Namaskarum Ara Vladimir Vladimir
Putin is also here Abir Tuli and
everyone else Sumita Agarwal Ram Ram
okay I'm going to discuss history today
first of all some of you sometimes have
the question of how to ask questions on
so that I can consider them for you know
for the ask a widget show what you do is
very simple if you want to ask me a
question you simply type down the
question and and and you and and u you
add the question in a comment in any of
the videos or maybe on the community
page. So you write the question as a
comment and use the hashtag askabijit.
So what I will do at the end of every
week or before I do one of these live
streams is I will spend a few hours
searching for that hashtag askabjit.
I'll go through all the questions that
have come with come up in the past few
days and I'll take as many as I can the
most interesting ones. So ask me
interesting questions. before asking a
question just search on my channel to
see if I have answered those such a
question or not before so that it's not
repeated sometimes people get frustrated
that I don't take their question but the
point is I've already taken their
question multiple times before perhaps
right so ask me questions that I haven't
answered before or maybe a different
variation of a question which would
throw up some interesting light on
something I haven't maybe thought about
and u if it's interesting if it if it
catches my interest I will certainly
take the question if it is something
that will provide value to all of the
viewers then it is then I will certainly
take it up. So that's how you ask
questions for this show. Today we
discuss history. History is very
important. You don't understand the
world unless you understand history.
There are so many geopolitics experts
out there who talk about what's
happening in the world based on what's
on the news. But to really explain
what's happening in geopolitics, you
have to have a proper background of the
history of whatever is happening. for
for example Ukraine. You don't
understand the Ukraine conflict without
understanding the history of the past
500 or 1,000 years. You to understand
the cause and effect. So that's why
history is so important and that's why I
keep doing these history live streams
and let us get going with some
questions. What are the questions that
we have today? I I I'll take at least 20
questions over the next couple of hours.
If there is time I'll take some
questions from the live chat as well. So
let let's see what do we have. Right.
Salon Mishra says why was England
seemingly okay with female female
monarchs as opposed to other countries
right so that's I took something similar
u in one of the recent episodes didn't I
uh it was about how the status of women
changed in Europe after the imposition
of Christianity
on the people of Europe and uh it the
status of women changed drastically once
Christianity became the dominant uh
religion in Europe. So before
Christianity, the women of Europe had
significant rights and privileges in
society. They were healers, they were u
teachers, uh they were decision makers,
they could own property, they could
initiate uh various legal proceedings,
they could initiate divorce, they could
keep their dowi and pass it on to their
descendants the way they wanted. They
could even rule. So all of these rights
and privileges were available to the
women of Europe before the imposition of
Christianity. And once Christianity was
imposed, it was like a 180°ree
turnaround for women. Women lost
essentially all rights. They became
property. They became like non-persons
in European society. It was said there
was a legal principle that said that the
husband and the women and the wife are
the same person and that person is the
husband. So women became non-persons.
women became erased from society in
Europe after the imposition of
Christianity and yet you have this
phenomenon in England in England that
you have female monarchs. So what's the
deal? How did that happen is the
question. Very interesting question.
Let's uh so
have you heard of something called the
celic law? Let's let's Google it so that
you get get the point of what I'm trying
to say. There was something called salic
law. S A L I C. S A L I C. All right,
let's check it out. What is the celic
law? Right. So also known as the salon
law. Let's take a take a look at what
Wikipedia has to say about this. Uh so
Wikipedia is superheroentric. So it's
going to give you a proper understanding
of what selic law is. Also known as
salon law. It was an ancient Frankish
civil law code compiled around 500 AD by
whoever the first and so on.
um it remained the basis of Frankish law
throughout the early medieval period and
influenced future European legal
systems. The best known tenate of the
old law is the principle of exclusion of
women from inheritance of thrones,
thiefs and other property.
The exclusion of women from the
inheritance of thrones, thiefs and other
property. Right? So it disenfranchises
women and the cyic law was adopted by by
Europe and that's why in Europe you
would not find any female ruler. So in
in in various European u kingdoms etc.
Uh if a king died without leaving a male
hair then the next king would be chosen
from somebody in his male
along the male lineage. So maybe a
nephew of his or or some male relative,
the closest male relative who is fit to
be on the throne, that sort of thing.
And that's how the next king would be
generally chosen based on that
principle. But no female descendant of a
king would ever be allowed to rule with
very few exceptions in Europe. Right?
So that was the deal in Europe. But and
and this became
uh it became a core principle especially
in the French u monarchy and other
European monarchies uh around the 14th
15th centuries AD. Okay. So that is
sailing law. But now in England things
were different. First of all you had
this great fantastic king called Henry
VIII. Fantastic guy, outstanding,
brilliant guy. He imagined that he was a
world conqueror etc. He imagined he was
the center of the world and very
interesting character and uh he he I
don't know how many ladies he married at
least four or five ladies more than half
of them had their heads chopped off
eventually for the sake of expediency uh
more than anything else and Bolain is an
example. Um
so Henry what he craved was a male child
but when he wanted to marry Anne Bolain
he was already married to Katherine of
Aragon and he wanted the pope to anal
his marriage based based on some flimsy
completely made up excuses.
Uh but the pope was unwilling to anal
the marriage and that's why what Henry
VIII did was incredible. He broke off
from the Vatican. He broke off his
allegiance. He he he severed his
allegiance to the Catholic Church and he
set up his own church of England, the
Anglican Church, which still is the main
church is the the basic uh overall
church of England today, the Anglican
Church. So he broke off from that and
that started off a chain of events that
eventually led to England becoming the
most powerful nation on the world for in
the world for quite some time
eventually. Eventually so that's where
it all starts. So Henry craved a male
child. Katherine of Aragon could not
produce a male child. She gave him uh
Princess Mary but no male child. Then he
had a mistress who gave a male gave him
a male child but the male child died.
Then he married Anne Bolain but Anne
Bolain again could not produce a male
child. She gave him Elizabeth, Princess
Elizabeth. Uh and so on. Eventually he
married Jane Seymour who produced a male
child but that male child died very
young. I think in his early teens or
something. and you can look up the exact
details.
So because Henry was left with no male
children, he therefore decided that
instead of passing on the throne to some
distant relative or whatever, I'm going
to pass it on to my daughters.
So he structured his succession such
that his first successor would be his
daughter, eldest daughter Mary and in
case she could not continue for whatever
reason or or passed away or did not
leave behind any male children then the
throne would pass on to his second
daughter Elizabeth.
Right? So after Henry VIII dies
tragically uh his daughter they you know
there was this small little episode of
Lady Jane Gray who they tried to install
on the throne. She ended up with her
head severed from the seivered from her
body. Her ghost still haunts the Tower
of London apparently. That's a
digression. So after Henry dies, there's
this little brief interlude of Lady Jane
Gray and then an uh sorry not Anne,
Mary, his daughter Mary becomes the
queen of England and that's because
England does not did not uh follow celic
law. So Mary became the queen of England
and she was not opposed to any by to any
significant extent by the nobility etc.
So she became the queen of England and
she ruled for quite some for for a
reasonable amount of time and she is
history has given her the title of
bloody Mary because she tried to undo
everything her father did and she tried
to you know restore the Catholic faith
and all that and she she did all kinds
of terrible things burned lots of people
at the stake alive and she also
eventually dies and that's how that's
when Elizabeth becomes the queen so
first you have this one queen that is
Mary bloody Mary and then you have her
sister half sister Elizabeth who becomes
the queen and that's the start of the
golden age of England the Elizabeth and
age that ends around 1600 AD roughly you
can look up the exact dates which is the
beginning of the English colonization
the very initial steps of the English
colonization occupation rather of India
so because
the English did not follow celic law
that's why they were okay with female
monarch so once you have the president
that set first with marry and then with
Elizabeth who turns out to be such a
brilliant ruler, it's hard to then argue
against a female ruler uh ruling
England. So one of the reasons uh why
you know a female ruler was not regarded
as a good thing apart from the Christian
anger etc is that a female see is that
because the royal families in Europe
they would marry among each other. So
typically a king's daughter would be
married to some prince from another
country and if the king's daughter
becomes the queen then her husband who
is a foreigner suddenly has incredible
influence in the running of the country
which is not necessarily always a good
thing. So that's one reason why it was
not seen as a you know as prudent to
have a female ruler. And if you look at
uh Queen Elizabeth II,
well, her husband has significant German
ancestry. Uh her mom, was it Victoria?
Most likely, she also, you know, there's
a lot of German ancestry today in the
English royalty because they allowed uh
queens, they allowed female monarchs to
rule the country. So, that was the deal.
And I hope this explains why England was
okay with female monarchs as opposed to
other countries because they did not um
follow Celic law despite being Christian
and all that. All right, next question.
Rohan Biri says the the Portuguese were
the first Europeans to land in India in
1498 while the East India Company was
formed in 1600. Why didn't the
Portuguese occupy India on the scale of
the British Empire despite having a
century long head start? You see, being
the first in the game isn't necessarily
going to give you success. And this is a
great example of that. And the same
applies in business also. You may be the
the person who discovered a new product
or or you know came up with an
invention, but it's not necessarily you
who's going to, you know, create a
monopoly. somebody else will do it
better than you. So sometimes so the
Portuguese
they you know Vasco the Gama that fell
out he landed in India in um 1498.
So and and the British did not even
begin thinking about India in a
structured way until the formation of
this joint stock company the East India
Company in 1600. So the Portuguese had
more than a century of a head start over
England. And yet what happened
eventually the English took over India
and the Portuguese were simply elbowed
away. Right? And you see similar things
happening in other parts of the world as
well. For example, in North America who
discovered Laafllorida who who made did
the first expeditions into the North
American, you know, what is now the
United States? It was the Spaniards and
also the French. But who ended up ruling
the United what is now the United States
and Canada, North America, all of it?
the English once again. So the English
came in much later and yet they ended up
ruling it. So there is something about
what the English do that's different
from what the other Europeans do. So
let's think about the Portuguese
approach
to whatever you know to colonial
practices, let's say to plunder.
So what was the main aim? What was the
main strategy of the of the of the
Portuguese? See the Portuguese first of
all you have to understand it's a very
small nation
around 1600 which is more than a century
after the Portuguese came to India first
around 1600 the population of Portugal
would have been about 1 million and the
population of England around 1600 was
about probably more than 4 million at
least 4 million so it's a 4 to1
advantage the English have right away
over the Portuguese now
the Portuguese
strategy Y was to establish a monopoly
in sea trade via control of ports,
coastal areas, ports, choke points,
Malaca, Hormos,
um, etc. Malika is something they they
controlled. Hormos, trade of hormos, the
Persian Gulf between the Persian Gulf
and the western Indian Ocean, they
controlled that as also for a while. Um
they also took over Du in Gujarat.
Um what else? Vasai in what is
Maharashtra? Wasai in Salet is which is
present day Mumbai Goa as well. So it's
all coastal areas and the Portuguese
were far-flung
at the same time they were trying to
control parts of India, the coastal
regions of India. there they were also
they also had you know possessions in
South America which eventually became
Brazil.
So they they were spread thin and their
strategy was to monopolize se
sea trade via ports and choke points in
trade routes. Now how was the Portuguese
enterprise colonial enterprise funded?
It was funded from by the crown of
Portugal, right? The the the the crown
of Portugal, the the king of Portugal
would fund this. So all the money came
from the crown and they had all these
scattered ports and scattered forts that
they were holding on to and uh that was
the deal with them and obviously uh it
was all focused on the navy. There was a
major naval focus and they would have
small armed forces in each of the forts.
small garrisons right in each of the
forts in each of the forts or ports
because the ports doubled as forts
now at the time when the Portuguese
started this this let's say policy
uh of holding on establishing and
holding on to forts and ports in India
at that time we're talking about the
what the 1500s that's when you don't
have a centralized empire in India you
have the Turk muggle kingdom OM which
eventually becomes the Muggal Empire.
But when the Portuguese first came, it
was not yet the Muggal Empire because it
becomes the Muggal Empire under Ash not
ash sorry the other guy Akbar Akbar
Jalaladin Jalaladin Akbar he is the the
king who transforms the kingdom into an
empire. So when the Portuguese were
doing the thing it was still a kingdom
and it was not central it was not you
know spread across India. uh India was
still fragmented in various kingdoms
etc. which is why the Portuguese were
able to uh establish ports and forts. Um
so that was the deal about Portugal.
Then you have British India
before we come to British India. So we
have the by the time the 1600s happen
the Muggal kingdom has become a muggle
empire. It's big. It's spread out and
they are absolutely not going to
tolerate any expansion of Portuguese
rule etc in India which is what the
Portuguese could not do a thing and
because they were spread so thin and
they had so many possessions across the
world and they were funded by the crown
and not by anybody else the funds were
less etc and which is why uh they did
not do well. Now when it comes to the
British, see their strategy was very
different. Their strategy was
to form joint stock companies which were
not funded by the crown.
Okay. Private companies, a bunch of
wealthy businessmen get together. They
pulled their funds. If if I put X number
of pounds, then I will re receive a
proportionate amount of stock in the
company. So it's a joint stock company
and the company will have a proper
charter. So it was a purely
commercialized commercial enterprise. So
the the objective was to trade
initially. Okay. Trade and uh gain some
territory small footholds of territory
in India and extract revenue from there.
And there was a deal. There was a deal.
So so the British are a nation of
traders. They are a nation of
shopkeepers.
and their only objective was to make
profits to extract whatever they could.
So their approach was very different
from the Portuguese. They did not try to
monopolize trade routes and and go and
hold various ports and forts across the
coastal regions of the world and u do
all that. They they established private
armies.
They equipped the private armies really
well with artillery and the latest
weapons and they set foot first where it
was in Surat then it was in what they
called Madras eventually what became
Kolkata and their first major
territorial grab was what is today
Bengal and they held on
unlike the Portuguese
and what happens is that eventually
there is Mughal decline the decline of
the Mughal empire the rise of the Marad
as the Maratas kick the Portuguese out
of Salset, of Wasai, of other places.
The the the Portuguese hold on to Goa
somehow. But the Maratas kicked them out
of everywhere else. But at that time the
British are established in Bengal and
slowly eventually because of the
infighting of the Marata Empire, the
British start slowly start making
inroads everywhere and that's how they
were able to grow. They were able to
outlast the Portuguese, outlast
everybody else. And because their
strategy was totally different. They
were a purely mercantile empire. Their
strategy was to hold territories, not to
just hold ports, but to hold
territories, go beyond ports and go and
acquire territories, acquire rights to
trade in the territories first and then
acquire the territories themselves when
the kingdoms or whatever the rulers
become weak to have private armies and
so on. And that's why once the Muggal
Empire declined, there was regional
fragmentation. The Marata Empire also
declined. Then they they went to war
with the Marata Empire and in 1818 or
wherever it was, they defeated the
Marata Empire.
So that's how the British were able to
able to prevail. They had a larger
economy. They you know they they they
grew their finance. They grew industry.
They they were a fully industrial state
and that's why they were able to pre
prevail. So,
so the time frame the the time window
for large scale territorial conquest
opened in India with the decline of the
Muggal Empire. Okay. In the 18th century
after the death of what's his name
Orurange which is what 1707 I think if
I'm not mistaken you can look it up the
exact date. So by the time Orurangzip
dies and the Muggal Empire starts
disintegrating that's when the window
opens up for territorial conquest large
scale territorial conquest conquest in
India right but by this time the
Portuguese empire was already in
long-term decline right and Britain was
entering its its uh expansionary stage
industrial stage with financial upswing
right so there's a mismatch in timing
the Portuguese are going down the
British are going up and they took full
advantage of the situ situation and by
the 19th century they were able to um
defeat the Maratas and that's why the
Portuguese
you see that's why the British were able
to um occupy India on the largest scale
and plunder India to their heart's
contest uh heart's content as opposed to
what the Portuguese were able to
achieve.
Rita Opadadyia says, "You have been
ignoring this question again and again.
Please explain about the confusion
bureaucracy in China and who was
Confucious." Okay, first of all, Retita
G, I did not mean to offend or upset
you. Look, uh
I I can only take about 20 or so
questions in each episode, right? But if
your question is good, I will eventually
notice it and qu and pick it up, which
is why I've done it today. Um
so who was first of all let's deal with
Confucious. Who was this person
Confucious? So he was a Chinese
philosopher, thinker, teacher, whatever
you want to call it. He was born in the
Shandong province. Where is the Shandong
province? It's uh south of Beijing and
east of Korea. If you want to I don't
think we need to look at the map for
this. You can look it up yourself.
Shandong province is south southish of
Beijing and and westward of Korea of the
Korean peninsula. That's Shandong
province. So he was born in the Shandong
province probably the fifth or sixth
century BC around that time. And his
ideas, his teachings became the core of
traditional chi Chinese culture, Chinese
philosophy, Chinese government, right?
Um and his teachings were both moral and
the political. Okay? And his philosophy
was all about cultivating virtuous
people, cultivating orderly
relationships.
And these ideas are are very well
aligned with having an orderly empire.
Right? So his ideas they influenced
China. They continue to influence China
and they also influenced various parts
of Eastern Asia as well. Right? So what
was his philosophy about? He's a
philosopher mainly. His philosophy is
about how to
how to become a good person and how to
form harmonious communities. So how do
you do this do these things? You
cultivate humanity. You cultivate
benevolence. You practice right
behavior. You practice propriety.
You become a junzi an exemplary person.
Right? And you do this by stressing by
by focusing on learning. With learning
comes knowledge and wisdom. So you focus
on learning. You f your society the the
ideal confusion society is a
hierarchical society
but not not a rigidly hierarchical and
oppressive society. It's a hierarchical
society that is that is characterized by
or moderated by benevolence. So a
benevalently hierarchical society with
social harmony. Okay. Um and confusion
says that you have to follow the proper
way in u you know personal life and
political life. So that is the confusion
philosophy kind of it's it's pretty I
mean it's it's not something you can
explain in 5 minutes but that's kind of
the gist of it. So this philosophy,
confusion philosophy, the confusion
thought, whatever you want to call it,
it became,
you could say a durable moral system for
family life in China, for education in
China and even politics in China. And
eventually the Chinese spread these
ideas to Korea, to Japan, even Vietnam
because Vietnam is a highly sinusized
society because of various Chinese
invasions and so on, right? Um
so what are the things that confucious
thought because we want to talk about
bureaucracy. So let's understand what
are the things that confus confusion
thought and philosophy influenced it
influenced
family family life family ethics you
need to be you know felial piety respect
for elders
um obligations to your kin to your
family and kin and family are spread
across society because we are all
cousins and aunts and uncles of each
other you know across across generations
so you have obligations to to to society
to your kin networks etc. So that's how
it influenced family life. It also
influenced education because it's all
about you know study you've got to study
uh you got to cultivate the self moral
self-cultivation obviously that happens
through study and the junzi the ideal
person becomes the model for not only
students but also for officials in
government and it influenced politics
very strongly. You must have I mean if
you are a long-term viewer of this
channel you would have heard me speaking
about the mandate of heaven that is a
central concept in the Chinese imperial
system. As long as the emperor has the
mandate of heaven he rules. The moment
he loses the mandate of heaven, the
emperor falls, the dynasty falls, and
there is a period of chaos and civil war
that typically lasts a century or so
before the next dynastic cycle starts.
The mandate of heaven. What is this
concept? This concept comes from
confusion philosophy. So Confucious his
view was that rulers should govern by
virtue and they should rule by setting
the right example.
And um Confucious said that the
legitimacy of a ruler is interconnected
or linked with their moral conduct.
Okay. So the mo as long as you are
morally upright and you are doing the
right thing and and serving society and
controlling society and being like a
father figure to society as long as you
do all these things you have the mandate
of heaven and when you lose the mandate
of heaven that's when your dynasty falls
and so on right so that's all about
confusionism about its role in society
its role in uh education its role in
family life and its role in politics now
what does it have to do with the
bureaucracy
Right? Confusion, bureaucracy, what what
is that? So if you go back to the first
millennium AD, you have the Tang dynasty
which was very strongly influenced by
India. You also have the Song dynasty
that comes probably later, right?
So from the Tang period onwards,
the Chinese civil service examination
system,
it became based on Confucian
literature, confusion classics. So the
confusion classics became the main
content of the uh civil services
education uh examination system. It
became the main content and it became
the ideological basis of the entire
bureaucratic examination system. So if
you wanted to become a bureaucrat which
would elevate you to very high and very
powerful status eventually if you're
good in society if you wanted to become
a bureaucrat a powerful person in
society in the empire then you had to
succeed in this exam and to succeed in
the exam you had to read you had to
understand the world through the lens of
confusion concepts confusion philosophy
you were you were supposed to value
Confu, you know, you were supposed to
embody concept uh confusion uh virtues
and ideals like loyalty, like valuing
the hierarchical order of order of
society, valuing confusion norms,
understanding what the mandate of heaven
is and so on. And if you were good at
this, if you could crack the exam, then
you could become a highranking official
eventually if you do the did the right
thing. So that was how you entered the
bureaucracy. So this was an officially
sanctioned form of confusionism. There
are various forms of confusionism but
this was the officially sanctioned form
of confusionism and the objective was to
legitimize the rule
of the empire of the emperor and to
shape the values and conduct and
behavior and comportment of the
bureaucrats of the officials who would
do the job of ruling the empire in the
name of the emperor. So um so this
connected administrative careers to
confusion philosophy, confusion ethics,
confusion morals, confusion values and
confusion political ideas and ideals.
Right? So that is the deal. So that's
and and this system has been going on
since at least the Tang dynasty and it
went on all the way until the fall of
you know China to the the westerners
during the opium wars. So historically
imperial governance was based on
confusion uh values, conf confusion
principles but it also incorporated
legalism, legalistic techniques,
centralized control, harsh law. So it
was a mixture of both. Now what is
legalism? Since we discussing confusion
bureaucracy, let's discuss legalism.
Confucianism and legalism are
essentially polar opposites.
These are two you could say ideologies
or philosophical worldviews.
Confucianism
views human nature in a certain way.
Legalism views human nature in the exact
opposite way. Okay. So legalism differs
from confusionism like a 180°ree
turnaround uh about how they how it
views human nature, how it views how
rulers should govern and uh and what is
it that holds an empire together.
Confucianism like I said emphasizes
virtue. It emphasizes moral education
and legalism is all about strict laws,
centralized power and harsh punishments.
Okay. So it's very different and and
Chinese governments empires they have
historically mixed the two things you
know employed aspects of confusionism
and employed aspects of legalism and you
see that you see that even today. So
legalism assumes that people are
fundamentally self-interested and
short-sighted and confusionism assumes
that humans are capable of goodness and
they they have good morals inside them
that need to be cultivated through
confusion, education, etc. And legalism
says that people respond only to
punishment, not to moral persuasion or
or education or whatever. And legalism
is about reforms. Okay. Legalism is
willing to break with tradition to
strengthen the state to for example if
you want to uh increase agricultural
output you can break with tradition. If
you want to make turn monks into workers
you can do that if you're a legalist.
But if you're confused you can't do that
right? And if you want to take the
workers take the peasants whose job is
to you know take care of agriculture. If
you want to take them and put them into
the military to build military power,
then it's fine with legalism. But it's
not fine with Confucianism. In
Confucianism, the uh the emperor is a
father figure, right? And uh he has the
mandate of heaven if he cares for the
people and does all all the good moral
things. But in legalism, the ruler is
absolutely sovereign and he doesn't have
any need to be a father figure. He is
supposed to use law, administrative
tech, administrative techniques and
punishments to keep the ministers, the
bureaucrats and the subjects, the
peasantry in line.
So that's the difference between
confusionism and legalism. See,
Confucianism is humane. It is virtue
centered and uh it it is not about
coercion. It's about uh it's it's about
persuasion more than coercion. And
legalism is all about coercion. about
looking about regarding coion as
indispensable to uh ruling a powerful
and orderly nation. So if you look at
the Chinese Communist Party today, if
you look at Mr. Xiinping, he does try to
portray himself as a father figure,
doesn't he? Right? He does portray
himself as kind of a grandfatherly
figure sometimes or a fatherly figure
sometimes. But the Chinese Communist
Party if you look at what its conduct
has been its actions have been
especially in the 20th century you don't
see too much confusionism there it's all
legalism right but today it's trying to
adopt a softer approach if you look at
the Chinese Communist Party's approach
towards Tibet you don't see confusionism
there right but today it's trying to at
least portray itself as as being more
humane and so so forth which
um and and and in doing so it's uh
merging confusionism with its basic
legalistic framework
and confusionism once again before I end
this there is no god in confusionism
yeah confusionism is not about it it
it's a you could say an atheistic
ideology or or philosophy there is no
place for god in confusionism
and the tang dynasty adopted
confucutionism as the as the state
bureau ratic thing uh as the basis of
the of the bureaucratic entrance
examinations. But the Tang dynasty was
very strongly influenced by Indian
Buddhist and Hindu ideas and and that
tells you that that Chinese society and
all societies and civilizations are
super complex. But anyway, I hope that
gives you some kind of understanding of
what Confucianism is, of what of who
Confucious was and why Confucianism,
Confucianism is still relevant in
Chinese society today and how the
Chinese Communist Party employs both
Confucianism and legalism
to rule the country.
Right. Okay. Next question.
Amish Amishara says, "What are the major
differences between the Spanish, French,
and English colonies in the Americas and
how did these differences affect the
native Americans?"
Right? So if you look at the
colonization or occupation of the
Americas which still continues, it was
done by multiple European powers. It all
begins with obviously the Spanish. Then
the French get involved. The English are
late entrance but they end up dominating
and and occupying the entirety of North
America and so on. So,
so all three of these European major
European powers had different approaches
in their occupation. Let's say
colonization because colonization is a
is a nice soft fuzzy term that is not as
harsh as occupation. So people like to
use colonization right as a term. So the
Spanish, the French and then the
English, their patterns were very very
different. Okay, their goals were
different, their economies were
different, their settlement patterns,
occupation patterns were different,
their attitudes were different when it
comes to either the capture of territory
or how to deal with the concept of race,
the issue of race because race is a very
big deal. And
these different approaches, goals, etc.
they shaped very different experiences
that Native Americans had at the hands
of these foreign occupiers. Okay. Um to
one extent to at one extreme you have
slavery, you have u you know coercion.
The entire population is is enslaved and
forced to do hard labor. Um that is
something the the Native Americans
experienced under Spanish occupation.
You also had cultural suppression that
happened against uh under Spanish
occupation. When it came to the French,
you had u sometimes alliances with the
French that the native Americans had uh
in doing the fur trade. And who was the
client in the fur trade? It was Europe,
right? And when it comes to their
experiences with England, it was total
despair, total loss, largecale
territorial loss, large scale
large scale war, ethnic cleansing,
genocide or displacement. All of that
came under England, right? So
what did each of these powers seek?
Let's begin with the Spanish who came
first. The Spanish, they were very
simple people. They sought gold. They
sought precious metals. They sought to
extract whatever they could in terms of,
you know, bullion, gold, silver,
precious metals. uh
whatever you know and they also sought
Christian conversion at the very out
from the very outset they sought
Christian conversion and the Spanish
were ruling over very densely populated
areas and they had systems like the
encommenda system that I've spoken about
in the past
the encommenda system essentially was a
system of slavery and the people who
were enslaved were were expected to do
very hard labor and produce a certain
amount of tribute or goods to be
exported to Spain every year or every
quarter or whatever it was. Right? So
the Spanish, they were very brutal. They
built cities on top of existing
Native American cities. They built
churches on top of destroyed Native
American temples. They would destroy the
temples and build churches churches on
top to show who's the boss, who's one.
The Spanish imposed a rigid racial
hierarchy. white man is the at the top
and the brown man is at the bottom and
they insisted on conversion. If they if
you would not convert, you would be
killed in various super brutal ways
ways, right? So that this destroyed
native religions. This destroyed the
native uh governance systems and so on.
And because of this and also the the
Spanish were very dirty.
So were the English. Um and they brought
in all these horrific diseases
uh to the Americas. Um so the native
Americans they establish they they
experienced catastrophic
population loss because of diseases
because of extremely harsh labor
conditions and uh
entire islands were depopulated like the
island of Hispanola completely
depopulated zero zero zero survivors
that sort of thing and sometimes the
native Americans would be relocated to
to towns or cities the Spanish would
construct so that you
to to concentrate labor in one place. So
this totally destroyed the society of of
whoever survived.
The Spanish also gave the status of
nobles to some of the indigenous uh
rulers or elites who would convert to
Christianity. Right? So they would be
given the status of nobles. They would
be given decent status in society. Then
the Spanish also intermar intermarried
with the nobles with the with the elite
of the uh indigenous societies. Then
this produced large scale mixed
populations and they the Spanish imposed
a cast system kind of thing based on the
color of his skin, lightness of his skin
and so on. So that's what happened with
the French the with the Spanish. The
French were different. They focused on
fur trade in North America. Okay. Um
they did not care about agricultural
agriculture the way the English did. So
this the French established scattered
outposts
uh and there's a you know they did not
establish large colonies large
plantation colonies like the Spanish did
in and later the English would do. The
French were only interested in fur trade
and French traders they relied on native
people uh they relied on native people
as economic partners. So the French
wanted to trade fur. They wanted to
acquire fur from North America and sell
it in Europe. They would acquire it in
from North America for for very little
money, for very little cost. They would
transport it to Europe and sell it at
high profit. Fantastic uh business
model, right? So for that the French
made the indigenous people their allies.
They did not oppress them. They did not
kill them more or less. Yeah.
um they would use Native American travel
routes, trade routes. They would
sometimes even marry uh into native
communities. And because of this, the
natives wherever the French were present
or the French had control, the natives
would retain control of their lands.
And um they also became partners of the
French in European power politics once
the French started having conflicts,
clashes with the with the Anglo and so
on. So there was something called the
French and Indian War, which you can
read about, right?
Um, and this this like I said this this
fur trade it the clients were European
clients, right? And this
tied the Native American tribes into the
European trade networks into um into
European markets and this led to clashes
between Native American tribes.
Intertribal conflict over what? Over
hunting territories, right? Because if
you want to sell fur to the furs to the
French, you need a large territory where
you will do hunting of reindeer of
caribou of of wolves of foxes of
rabbits, mink, whatever. So you need
large hunting territories because that's
what gives you the first and that's
valuable. So then it led to intertribal
conflicts
and eventually it was devastating when
the French power declined. Now when it
comes to the English, okay, the English
were all about permanent occupation.
They were not about trade like the
French. They were about permanent
occupation, agricultural settlement.
What the English sought to do was to
create a society that either replicated
England, English society, or improved
upon English society. They did not want
to rule over large native populations,
the English. They wanted to create a
better version of England in the
Americas. How do you do it? Permanent
settlement.
Wipe out forests to create agricultural
land. Migrate your settle migrate your
families and settle them on this land.
Create private land ownership on land
that is not yours.
Right? So the English colonists they
created separate communities. Okay? They
did not do any most likely very little
intermarriage with the native Americans.
And what the English would do is that if
the native land was not farmed in
English ways then they would say that
this land is unused which means we can
take it. And obviously the natives did
not farm in the English ways. So they
use this so-called agricultural argument
to justify taking native territory. So
we're doing it legally. See this land is
unused. It is not farmed the way we
English farm. The natives are doing some
some wild, you know, backward things
over there. So it's unused land. So that
justifies it justifies us taking it
legally. So the English regarded the
natives
as
essentially agricultural pests. What is
an agricultural pest? Rabbits, deers,
birds. What do they do? They eat your
agricultural produce. They eat your
cabbages and cauliflowers and lettuce
and and carrots. The birds, they eat
your grain, right? So what do farmers
do? they shoot those animals whether
it's rabbits or birds or deer or
whatever. If you are doing chicken
farming or some other farming then foxes
come and eat those. Wolves come and eat
those. So you want to shoot the foxes
and wolves and coyotes.
These are called agricultural pests in
the eyes of farmers of agriculturalists
whose uh livelihood can be affected by
these animals. The English regarded the
native Americans the same way farmers
regard certain species of creatures
animals as agricultural pests. What do
you do? You shoot. Yeah. So what was the
effect of this continual land loss,
relentless loss of native lands?
The English would first sign, you know,
draw up a treaty in the English language
and ask the native chief to put a X or a
cross or something which means now we
have a legal agreement which gives us
certain rights and then they would once
it is the the time is opportune they
would break those treaties and this
would lead to violent clashes with the
natives because the settlers they were
their their greed for land for territory
was insatiable. Where do the natives go?
Right? So this led to displacement of
the natives. This led to massacres of
the natives. This led to genocide of the
natives. This led to ethnic cleansing of
the natives and all the territory was
lost. And then the the natives whoever
survived somehow they were put on put on
little areas called reservations where
nothing grows, barren land which is
useless. Yeah. So the English occupiers
were completely disent disinterested in
integrating native communities into
their society. So natives were they had
the choice of either moving away or
become second or third class citizens at
the margins of English society, English
occupied society or resist militarily
which guarantees death because the
English had far superior organization,
far superior ways of applying organized
violence
and eventually the natives today they
are conquered and subjugated secondass
citizens.
in the Americas. That's the deal.
Terrible, terrible story,
part of history.
Nirvana Shank says, "How did
enlightenment ideals of liberty and
equality coexist with the rise of
European colonial empires
and can the ethical contradictions of
the period be reconciled historically?"
Right. Thank you for your attention to
the matter. Yes sir.
So libert enlightenment ideals of
libertal
that that's a French revolution but the
this all comes from the so-called
European enlightenment where you have
liberty and equality
but how can liberty and equality coexist
with slavery is what Nirvana Shanks is
asking right so
these ideals liberty equality
they actually coexisted with European
can impose slavery on all these
so-called colonies
because because of very clever
ideas. See many thinkers in Europe they
they narrowed down the classification of
who counted as fully human or who
counted as citizens. So these
principles, liberty, egalit, liberty,
equality, they sound like they're
universal principles, right? But these
Europeans then turned these principle
into principles into selective rights
by by tweaking what what is the meaning
that by tweaking the definition of the
term human in the term citizen. Okay. So
before we proceed to colonial empires,
let's talk about European society.
So these many of these enlightenment
writers, okay, what did they say? All
men are equal.
Now what happens to women?
Women, what happens? Nothing. Women
don't exist. Women, women are
subordinate. Women are non-persons in
European society, Christian society.
That's how it was. I kid you not.
And when they said that all men are
equal, they applied that to men who had
property, men who had wealth, not the
refra, not the, you know, the peasants
who toiled on on on a feudal lord's
property. No, not those people. The the
males, the European males who who are
wealthy and who have property, they are
the ones who are equal. So even in
European society there was not this this
this this
did not apply equally to all human
beings. Women were not part of this term
all this this statement that all men are
equal and even when it comes to men it
only applied to people who had wealth
and property and it certainly did not
apply to colonized people. Okay. So the
empires could claim that they gave
rights to people at home, males at home,
but they could deny those rights abroad.
So you know the Europeans had these
fantastic ideas about what it means to
to be a civilization, what it means to
be civilized. They had ideas about
civilization. They had about ideas about
race. They had ideas about historical
stages of development.
Historical stages of development. So
certain populations are are essentially
prehistoric or a you know they are not
sufficiently developed to be called uh
civilized people for example they are
too backward or they're too brown or
they're too black or whatever right or
they're not Christian enough or they're
not Christian at all so they can't be
called civilized that sort of thing. So
by by you know by introducing such
nuances they could they could portray
colonized populations of territories
they had grabbed. They could portray the
populations as people who are not yet
ready for full equality, full liberty.
Right? So by doing this they could they
were able to justify conquest. They were
able to justify forced labor. um they
were able to justify u this
paternalistic attitude of the Europeans
as steps towards uh eventually reaching
an allegedly higher European standard of
civilization. Right?
You will also know that the Americans
they had a constitution. They they have
a constitution, right? Um whatever it
says it calls the the natives as as
what? Savages. No, that's the
Declaration of Declaration of
Independence, the US Declaration of
Independence, if you read it, it uh
portrays the natives as savages. But the
Americans have a constitution. And this
Constitution was allegedly ratified by
the people of America. But was it? Well,
it wasn't ratified by women. It wasn't
ratified by by the natives. It wasn't
ratified by the enslaved Africanamean
people. It wasn't even ratified by white
men who did not have property.
So, you know, that's the kind of game
they would play. So they
created cultures, they created
societies, okay, in which the freedom in
which not everyone was a citizen and
freedom was for the those who were
called citizens was built upon the
slavery of those who had been conquered
and enslaved
and who would do all the labor for the
for the so-called citizens. So that's
how it was. You see uh so European so
non-Europeans had to be first educated
and how do you educate someone through
hard labor so that they can you know
become more attuned with the European
way of doing things uh so on so that's
how it was it was all racism it was all
justification for conquest for slavery
for genocide for forced displacement for
uh ethnic cleansing for having uh
millions of people work as slaves while
you enjoy the benefits of that Right. So
that all came out of enlightenment.
Enlightenment. So the the these these
thoughts that came out these thoughts
and slogans and ideals that came out of
enlight of the so-called enlightenment
or enlightenment thought they actually
gave the Europeans tools for
legitimizing
slavery for legitimizing genocide and
whatn not. Can we can we reconcile these
ethical contradictions of this period
historically? Well, how do you reconcile
these contradictions? Right? You you
can't it cannot be justified. You can
perhaps contextualize it. You can say
that all whatever happened was a product
of economic interests of the Europeans.
It was a product of the entrenched
racism, inherent deep rooted racism of
the Europeans and it was it was
consequences of um the limited notions,
the limited ideas of what counted as a
citizen or even among the subjects what
counted as a person who had some kind of
rights or did not have rights. Right? So
it's it's uh this entire period the
so-called colonial period the period of
the destruction of the world by the
Europeans it is a history of rapacious
occupation rapacious plunder and
domination
of people millions hundreds of millions
of people dressed in the language of
progress.
Okay. They used they used the
terminology the vocabulary of rights of
equality of self-determination
human rights democracy today same way
and they used it to just to to justify
uh their domination and all the the
abuses and and and and atrocities they
did. So you can't you can't reconcile
these things. And the same kind of
attitude persists today. Today they will
give you slogans about human rights and
freedom and democracy while being the
worst abusers of human rights and
freedom and democracy. Nothing really
has changed. Well, there we have it.
Okay.
Amisha Mishra says, "How did Rhodesia,
now known as Zimbabwe, decide who could
vote and who couldn't? Was it based on
your ethnicity, your income, etc.?
Interesting question. Where is Rhodesia?
It doesn't exist anymore. But it does
exist. The region exists, but now it's
called something else. Like Amisha says,
it's called Zimbabwe. Where is Zimbabwe?
Let's find out. Indians would be
somewhat familiar with Zimbabwe because
of the sport of cricket. Because there's
a Zimbabwe cricket team, which used to
be good in the past. It's not so not so
good anymore. So
if you are in India, we go westwards.
And here we have Zimbabwe which is to
the north of South Africa and to the
east of Botswana and to the west of
Mozambique that is where we have
Zimbabwe the capital is Harare. So this
region this this country was was
in the 20th century until what the 1970s
late '7s you can look up when it
happened until then it was called
Rudesia. It was named after the great
barbarian Cecil Ruds after whom on whose
name you you have this fellowships RDS
fellowships that Indians still enjoy
sometimes. So that is what Rhdesia used
to be. Okay. And uh who ruled Rhdesia?
English-sp speakaking people. A bunch a
small number of white people ruled the
country. And uh who were the subjects?
The black people who did not have too
many rights. So what was the deal?
Did Rudesia
have universal adult suffrage? Did they
allow everyone to vote or did they
restrict who could vote? And what were
these restrictions based on? So, first
of all, Rudiga did not have universal
adult suffrage. What does it mean to
have universal adult suffrage? It means
that anyone who is legally an adult is
allowed to vote. India has universal
adult suffrage. Anyone who is above the
legal age for being an adult can vote in
any election in India. In Rhdesia, you
don't you did not have that. So the vote
in Rhodesia, the right to vote in
Rhdesia was restricted. You had to meet
certain requirements. You had to meet
certain qualifications. What kind of
qualifications? Like u like Amisha says,
it was it was not ethnicity.
It's it's it was very cleverly done. Um
it was based on requirements
on on on income on property
on education and residency. So you have
to be a resident of the nation etc. But
you need to needed to have a certain
amount of income minimum amount of
income a minimum amount of property.
Taxation also mattered how much tax you
paid minimum amount of tax that you had
to pay also education. Right? And on
paper, these rules applied to all races
on paper.
But the minimum level, the thresholds,
they were set in such a way that mostly
it was the white so qualified and only a
very small minority of the black natives
qualified. Most of them could not. So
they had two voter categories, two voter
roles, A- roll and B- roll. B-roll is
very cinematographic, but it's not that.
So, you had the A voter rule and the B
voter rule. The A- roll was obviously
the Europeans, the whites, and the
B-roll was predominantly the natives,
the Africans. So, to register to vote,
you had to satisfy these minimum levels
of income, property, ownership, property
ownership and educational levels, etc.
Now the
colonial pol policies were such that
Africans had far lower incomes than the
whites. Africans probably very few
Africans were allowed to own land right
and most Africans had did not have any
access to European kind of schooling
that sort of thing. So because of this
these so-called the supposedly neutral
qualifications or thresholds etc. They
excluded the overwhelming majority of
black adults from the right to vote.
So a few lakh a few hundred,000 white
people held the majority of the elected
seats and millions of black people. they
only had a handful of seats and most of
these seats were chosen indirectly
through nominations from chiefs or
whatever not by the popular vote. So the
theory and practice are very different
in in theory anybody meeting these
criteria was allowed to vote but in
practice these tests these these
criteria were designed and maintained in
such a way that they preserved white
dominance in a black majority country.
So that was the deal. So it so these
criteria were built on a racially
unequal society
and the right to vote was clearly
demarcated on racial lines. Uh even
though it was not explicitly demarcated
or defined by ethnicity and these are
the this is how you can use laws
to exclude people even though they sound
neutral on paper and it's it's not just
Rhdesia where such things happen.
You can look closer to home and examine
certain lows and you will find that
though they sound neutral, they are
actually very skewed. Very interesting.
All right.
Shub says we all know about atrocities
done by the axis in the second world
war. What's the axis? It is the alliance
of Germany, Italy and Japan. That's the
axis, right? So we all know about the
atrocities done by the axis in the
second world war. We don't have to
discuss that. We all know right? Please
tell us about the other side too as
their war crimes are often hidden. Well
you see
it's something that's not taught in your
schools. It's something that no textbook
will write about.
And so it's
it's prudent not to talk about it in too
much detail. Yeah. But there was
a significant period of ethnic cleansing
of Germans and also Italians after the
second world war. Okay. So the mythology
is the the what what we are told what
the Hollywood mythology etc is that the
allies were the good guys. They were
bringing freedom to the people of
Europe. They were bringing freedom to
the people of Germany. They are bringing
law and order to the people of Germany
and to Europe. Right? The truth is that
it's uh this the truth is complicated.
The allies were often just as brutal as
the Germans. Okay.
Um look at the end of the day. The
Americans and their allies, they were
not fighting for human rights and
freedom and democracy and all that
wonderful stuff. They were fighting for
power and control. They were fighting to
create a new world order based on
whatever benefited them. So they wanted
as much power, as much control, as much
domination of the world as possible. And
Germany was a problem for them. That's
why in Japan also, Italy did not matter
that much. So that's why u they were
fighting the war. At the end of the day,
the allies won, the Americans won
actually. And that was the the the
beginning of what became the American
Empire which still rules the world. So
you may not have heard of these
territories, German territories called
Pomerania,
East Prussia,
Slesia
where you had German populations that
lived there. Today
these territories are part of either
either uh Poland or or Russia
or the Czech Republic or Austria or some
you know it's divided among these
countries and you you probably don't
have any Germans living there. So more
than 10 million maybe up to 15 maybe 10
to 15 million Germans were evicted from
these territories.
It's called ethnic cleansing by the way.
Yeah, they were evicted from these
territories, driven out and uh
what's the death toll? More than 2
million perhaps? More than 2 and a half
million perhaps. So the death toll could
be between several hundred thousand to 2
and a half million. Maybe more, maybe
whatever. Right? So it's it's a massive
it's it's a it's a massive massive u
case of ethnic cleansing that happened
in the aftermath of the end of the
second world war but you won't find uh
any history textbook speaking about this
right um and many such atrocities were
committed during the second world war
I'm not trying to nobody can deny what
the Germans did the holocaust nobody can
deny that no one's even trying to deny
No one can deny what the Japanese did,
right? Nanjing and so much more. All
those things happen. But it's not like
the allies don't do anything. They were
sometimes equally bad. Nobody can deny
what the Soviets also did. The Soviet
atrocities were also terrible. So the
Nazis committed horrific crimes, war
crimes, no question. So did the Soviets.
So did the Japanese.
Italians, not so much. Nothing not
nothing comparable to the that scale.
But even the allies did similar things.
But you don't speak about that today. So
I won't go into too much detail about
this. But uh you know that's the deal
right.
Amisha says Rajuts of the Hindu Shahi
dynasty of Kabul, Zabul and Kandahar
held their posts and defeated the most
indestructible force in the world
Islamic caliphate for two centuries.
Persia fell in 22 years, Egypt in 10
years. But the Hindu Shahi uh they
fought for over two centuries. The Hindu
Shahi dynasty first of all
you know
when the Hindu Shahi dynasty ruled over
Gandhar
for about for about two centuries let's
say okay roughly two centuries at that
time they were not called Rajputs. This
term Rajput emerged in about 5 600 years
ago. But the people who were are
retrospectively called Rajputs, they did
not call themselves Rajput. So first of
all, we have to understand that this is
a newer term. It did not exist. The term
Rajput did not exist at the time of the
Hindu Shai dynasty and the dynasties of
the first millennium AD. But today they
are classified as Rajputs. First of all,
we we're not quite sure if uh what are
the origins of the Hindu Shahai dynasty.
So before the Hindu Shahi dynasty, okay,
we had the Turk Shahis who ruled in
Gandhar which is northern western
Pakistan, Afghanistan etc. That overall
region is called Gandhar.
The Turk Shahis were the descendants of
the Schwa Hunas the Huns.
The horns who tried their best to
conquer India during the Gupta Empire
and who failed.
They were driven off repeatedly by our
great emperor Scandag Gupta. But after
Scandupta's death, the Horns prevailed
and they swept into India and they
eventually assimilated into the Indian
population. They became Indians. Their
descendants live all among us.
So they established the Huns. They
established a dynasty in Gandhar which
came to be known as the Turk Shahis. See
the Turks
are descendants of the Huns. So this
Hunic descended dynasty in Gandhar came
to be known as the Turk Shahis because
the Hun Turks are the same thing. And
the Turk Shahis they ruled from the 7th
century AD to the 9th century AD roughly
roughly 150 to 100 years.
They adopted Hinduism and Buddhism. And
the Turk Shahis, descendants of Huns who
were by blood Turk, they became Hindus
and Buddhists. And for one and a half or
two centuries, they fought the Abbasid
caliphate
to safeguard India. They fought the
Abbasad Khalifhat for nearly two
centuries.
Okay. The Turks fought for India. They
fought to safeguard India from the
Abbasad caliphate. Eventually in the 9th
century AD somewhere around that time
the Turkis finally were defeated. Their
last king was forced to convert to Islam
and one of his ministers possibly a
Brahman possibly Chhatria we don't know
quite he took over
the leadership and he established a new
dynasty which came to be known as the
Hindu Shahi dynasty. The Hindu Shahis
were shvites.
They moved on from the Gandhara script
and they started using the Shahara
script. Okay? And they ruled from the
9th century AD to the 11th century AD.
The Hindu the the the Turk Shahis fought
the Abbasid caliphate and they spent two
year two centuries roughly defending
India from the Abbasids.
They eventually had to convert to Islam.
They were defeated. The Hindu Shahis
they fought not the Abbasid Khalivid
they fought the Gaznavi Empire.
Okay. So they did that for a couple of
centuries. What was the Gaznavi Empire?
It was based out of Gazni. Eventually it
was based out of Gazni in Afghanistan in
Gandhar. And the Gaznavids were Turk in
nature in by ethnicity. They were Turk.
They were of Mamluk descent. What does
it mean Mamluk? It means they were freed
slaves. They were slave soldiers who
eventually became rulers. Right? Uh so
that was the Gnavi Empire and the Hindu
Shahis they fought the Gaznavids for
roughly two centuries.
And
you can call them Rajputs, you can call
them whatever. There are different
accounts, varying accounts. Some Turk
accounts say that the the Hindu Shahis
were of Brahman origin. Some other
accounts are that they were of Chhatri
origin. It doesn't matter. They fought.
It makes them warriors and you could
call them Rajputs. Um so yeah they they
defended India for two centuries from
the Gnavids and eventually you had the
they also were defeated right that as we
know. So you have these centuries of
resistance
to Arabic
and and Turic invasions
of India by the Turk Shahes by the Hindu
Shahes by various Rajput kingdoms in the
north and west of India that your
history textbooks and your teachers
won't teach you about and that's a
travesty we should know about these
things. So I'm glad this question has
been asked. I appreciate that very much.
Amisha again says, "Did Adolf Hitler
actually derive inspiration from US
policies towards Native Americans for
the Holocaust?"
Let's understand this. We know what
Adolf Hitler did. The Holocaust of it is
said 6 million Jews, right? Uh in
various horrific death camps and
whatnot. Oshwitz, Soibbor,
Ribbina and and so on. Horrific chapter
of history. not fun to talk about. So
we'll not discuss it but where did Adolf
Fetra get the idea from? Where did he
get the inspiration from? Did he get
this inspiration of what he did to the
Jews from US policies towards Native
Americans? And that's the question
Amisha is asking. Very interesting
question. What is the truth? The truth
is very interesting.
So Adolf Fitler was indeed
someone who studied US policies, US
racial policies towards the blacks and
the native Americans. and US
expansionist policy. The US,
how the US expanded relentlessly
westwards
from its initial base on the east coast
of what is today the United States and
then it expanded relentlessly,
inexorably westwards, grabbing and
gobbling up more and more Native
American territory, displacing the
Native Americans, genociding them,
massacring them if required, eventually
taking the whole continent essentially,
right?
So Hitler,
he studied this in detail. He looked
upon what the Americans did as a model
for what he should do in Europe. But it
was not necessarily the single
straightforward blueprint for the the
Holocaust that he committed. So and how
do we know this? See Hitler wrote about
this in Minecom. Minecom is this book
that he wrote my struggle
very unreadable book actually I tried
more than 20 years ago um pretty hard to
read but he wrote about this in mine and
Hitler's writings speak about the fact
that he regarded the the United States
as a racial state as as one of the most
successful racial states on the world in
in the world because of its successful
successful immigration restrictions
because of the segregation system that
the United States had at the time and
because of the conquest of the western
continental frontier that the Americans
successfully carried out. He was a huge
fan of the United States. He was very
pleased that a a Nordic population,
white skinned population had displaced
inferior brownskinned indigenous people
and conquered their territory. And they
had structured citizenship, they had
structured immigration on the basis of
racial lines, on the basis of so-called
white superiority. And Hitler said that
this is a great model. It's it sets a
great precedent for what his goals were
in Europe, especially Eastern Europe,
the German uh the Nazi uh desire for a
lib in Eastern Europe to to conquer
Eastern European territories and settle
Germans there. And what should be done
with the people who lived there? Deal
with them the way the Americans dealt
with the native Americans. Yeah. So the
so the Nazis, not just Hitler, but the
Nazis, they they studied all of this.
They studied American laws,
anti-misogenation laws, uh the Jim Crow,
the segregation uh laws and policies,
etc. The gym the Jim Crow rules or laws
the Americans had. They studied the
citizenship and immigration laws or
rules that favored white Europeans and
excluded non-whites.
They examined laws that dealt with the
Indian problem, the Native American
problem, reservation policies and how to
treat the natives and their native
nations. Um to treat them as as people
who are under your jurisdiction, under
your subjugation who are not sovereign.
Don't treat them as sovereign peoples.
Treat treat them as as wards. Yeah.
So Hitler studied all of this and uh
they saw the American conquest of
America as the as uh as the precedent
for the Nazi
um desire for a leven in Eastern Europe.
So um
and you can see that the way the
Americans dehumanized
the Native Americans, you know, the way
they forcibly removed them, the way they
they the way they forcibly removed them
from the their territory, the way the
Americans used hunger as a weapon
against the Native Americans, all of
this the Germans would eventually
replicate when it comes to the people
they whose territories they conquered
and the people they subjugated. So you
can see there are a lot there are a lot
of the Nazi actions were you could say
influenced
by American actions in the 18th and 19th
centuries even 20th century in in a
variety of ways right so they
consciously used aspects of US policy of
US race law as models and as
justification for what they did so
Hitler was a huge fan of the United
States right he looked up to the United
states. Um,
so that was the deal. But when it comes
to the Holocaust, the the the genocide
of the Jews that the Germans that the
Nazis committed, uh, you could say it's
it's not just based on what the
Americans did to the to the native
populations of North America. It was
also based on anti-semitism,
which, you know, in Europe there's a
2,000-y old history of anti-semitism.
So, it was also based on that, not just,
you know, based on what the Americans
did. It was also based on various German
colonial practices. It was based on the
experiences the Germans had in the first
world war. It was based on Nazi ideology
also racial superiority, the Uber mench,
that sort of thing. So all these
different influences came together
including the very important model that
they copied from the US. Um and that
gave rise to
well the displacement of people in
Eastern Europe.
um the concentration camps that the
Germans that the Nazis set up, the
systematic genocide of the Jewish
people, all of that. So the US policies
towards Native Americans are one strand
of influence
in
um in the way the Nazis behaved. It's
not the only thing, but it was
definitely a major and and very
important influence on the Nazis and on
Hitler's policies and behavior and
actions.
Salon Mishra says in what language what
language did emperor Ashoke use
to speak what was his mother mother
tongue the language he used for talking
for speaking what about Chandra Gupta
Moria so Chandra Gupta Moria was Ashok's
grandfather
what language did they use
so if you look at Ashok's inscriptions
they are in magadi praarit in in the
Magad region and in other parts of India
but not always. Right? If you look at
northern India, northern India,
northwestern India which is which is now
Afghanistan over there you will find
their their inscriptions in other
languages like Aramaic also because you
know there was a place where you had
people from other countries coming in
from other kingdoms other regions of the
of Eurasia coming in. So you would have
to write those inscriptions in in
international languages. So you does
Ashok have inscriptions in Greek
definitely Aramaic but I'm not sure but
if you look at his u inscriptions
south of Gandhar you will find that they
are mostly written in madiar
which would indicate that that was not
just the state language the official
language of the state because if you
write an inscription in that language it
means it's the official language of the
state so most likely the official
language of the state was magi pakarit
and that would also have been is the
language he used to communicate most
likely. Beyond that we don't have any
further information. So whatever we say
has to be based on whatever evidence we
have.
So there is madi there is ardamadi pak
perhaps right and that would have been
the language of not just ashok but also
his grandfather and also probably
vishnuishaka who would also have known
sanskrit obviously because he wrote the
art chastra in sanskrit.
So yeah and then we have later on the
Kushan Empire that employed multiple
languages.
Um we also have the Gupta Empire that
used classical Sanskrit in its official
communications. Right?
So you have various empires using
different languages for official
communications. And it's very
interesting too.
I mean what would that language have
sounded like?
We have all these historians
with PhDs who hold professorships in
Indian universities
but they don't want to do this research.
What would a conversation in Madi Prait
have sounded like? Why can't we
reconstruct that language which is
definitely going to be an upper branch
language of Sanskrit. So it will not be
that difficult to reconstruct but nobody
has bothered to do these things.
Everyone focuses on Pali for some
reason. Pali Pali Pali Pali. What about
Madi Pakarit? What about Maharashtri
Prait?
The ancestral language of the Marathi
language.
There are so many praits that were
spoken in India in various parts of the
subcontinent at different times in
India. Nobody has bothered to
reconstruct these languages. So it's
it's uh sad that that's the case. Our
historians clearly have specific agendas
and they will stick to those those
agendas.
Uh but yeah, so the language of Emperor
Rashok was most likely Magadi Praarit
from about 2,000ish
BC or two 2,200ish
BC around that time.
Swapil Mishra says, "What do we know
about the first humans who arrived in
the Indian subcontinent and how do they
compare to early humans in Africa and
the rest of Asia?"
Early humans. So look, when we talk
about early humans,
we can talk about the
early archaic humans and the early
modern humans. The early modern humans
are homo sapiens, right? We are the
modern humans and the earliest homo
sapiens where their fossil remains were
discovered in North Africa and those
date back to about 400,000 years before
today. A place called Jibel Hud in North
Africa. So the oldest known fossils of
homo sapiens date back to about 400,000
years ago. But the oldest evidence of
homo sapiens in the subcontinent,
it it dates back to probably about
80,000 years before today.
But that's not the oldest evidence of
humans in the subcontinent. We have
older humans
whose remains and evidence have been
discovered in the subcontinent. That is
most likely Homo erectus.
The oldest evidence of the presence of
Homo erectus in India in the
subcontinent is about 1 and a half
million years old
and that's in two archaeological sites.
One is in Tamil Nadu, one is in
Karnataka. And they have discovered
indirect evidence of the presence of
Homo erectus.
How so? So they haven't discovered
fossil remains of Homo erectus bones.
They haven't discovered that. But they
have discovered stone tools that were
clearly made by human beings. And how do
you date how old stones are? Because you
can't do carbon dating of stones. You
date them based on how how deep they
were buried. in the archaeological
record and and based on that you can
kind of roughly estimate the date around
which these
artifacts were created. So that dates
back to about 1 one and a half million
years before today. Homo erectus.
Then you have archaeological evidence
from the Nurmada valley. That's there's
a village whose name I can't recall. You
can look it up where
fossil evidence of ancient humans was
found and that's about 300,000 years old
in the Nermada Valley and that once
again is Homo erectus most likely
and what they discovered was a skull cap
you know the top of the skull that part
and a clavicle you know the collar bone
the collar bone is this bone here so
they found a cavicle and u the top of
the skull the skull cap and that is most
likely Homo erectus or the Nurmada
Valley variant of Homo erectus and that
is about 300,000 years old.
When it comes to the oldest Homo
sapiens, there is evidence of Homo
sapiens surviving the Toba super volcano
eruption in the subcontinent. So the
Toba super volcano eruption did not
happen in the subcontinent. It it
happened in Indonesia, what is now
Indonesia. It happened about 74,000
years ago. And there's evidence of a
layer of ash from that super volcano
eruption in various parts of India. And
in one archaeological site you find
evidence of stone tools under the layer
of ash which means it precedes that and
also just after the layer of ash just
above it which means humans in India
survived the tuba super volcano eruption
that is homo sapiens
most likely.
So the out of Africa migration happened
between 80,000 to 60,000 years ago
roughly. We don't know for sure exactly
but yeah so India was the first place
where homo sapiens properly set you know
set up shop
and uh we had a thriving population of
homo sapiens here and we are the the
descendants of those early uh settlers.
So yeah, so our ancestors 80,000 74,000
years ago they survived the Toba super
volcano eruption and genetically we know
that India has the oldest non-African
populations in the world. When it comes
to
when it comes to matrinal
uh genetic lineages, mitochondrial haplo
groups uh haplo groupoups m and mn m and
n are the oldest non-African matrinal
haplo groups or lineages in the world
genetic lineages and both originate in
the Indian subcontinent and the oldest
non-affrican patrineal
genetic lineage
which is haplo F which is a Y
chromosomal hyper hyper group. It is
also something that originated in India.
So that's what we know from the genetic
record. The fossil record of homo
sapiens in India is very fragmentaryary
especially you know the older record
because nobody has done bothered to do
archaeology in India. Nobody cares.
Right? If we do
take up the bother to do archaeology,
you will find, I expect, staggering,
stunning discoveries that will rewrite
the history of humanity
because India was the first place where
homo sapiens properly settled down after
the out of Africa migration. It's in
India that that small group of migrants
came and settled and established a large
burgeoning growing population which
eventually numbered in the millions. And
it's from India that various groups of
travelers of homo sapiens eventually
went in different directions across
Eurasia and settled down and you know
set up human populations there and we
see that in the genetic record. The
oldest lineages both male and female
non-affrican lineages are Indian. So if
our archaeologists decide to wake the
hell up and start doing archaeology,
start doing what they are paid for, then
we will find stunning discoveries in
India
of the origins of the oldest
non-affrican homo sapiens population.
It's just waiting to be discovered.
Someday it'll happen hopefully.
Okay. Sam says as you said a country
needs a just cause to go to war against
another country then what was the just
cause of the Soviet Union to attack
Afghanistan
you see just causes are for weak
countries
if you are super powerful you don't need
any just cause
you can bend the laws as per your whims
and desires rules-based world order it's
only for the weak if I set the rules I
can always rewrite the rules and do
whatever I want I can go and flatten
Iraq if I want
I can go and flatten some other country
if I want.
Yeah.
So it's the the just cause for war. It's
only for weak countries. Now let's come
to what we are discussing here. Soviet
Union and Afghanistan. The Soviet
invasion of Afghanistan which happened
in 1979 December probably 25 December
1979 if I am if I recall correctly. You
can look up the exact date which may
differ perhaps or maybe not whatever.
So what was the just cause for the
Soviets or the cause of the Soviet
invasion of Afghanistan. So as always we
have to go back in history to understand
the cause and effect chain to understand
what caused all of this.
So let's go to the 19th century. See
when I was first for the first time
asked about the history of the Ukraine
war. Why did this war happen? I went
back to 1000 AD. So I am doing you a
favor. I'm only going to the 19th
century here. 19th century we had the
Sikh Empire. The Sikh Empire whose great
ruler was Shri Ranjit Singh. Maharaj
Ranjit Singh and he liberated Kashmir
from the Afghans. By the time the
Afghans of Gandhar had converted fully
to Islam and they had conquered Kashmir
and they had done a horrific atrocities
to the people of Kashmir. So Maharajjit
Singh liberated Kashmir from the Afghans
and he also grabbed
significant Afghan territories as
punishment
as a punitive measure.
So that was the western and northern and
western frontier of the of the Sikh
empire
which included significant pashon
territories.
Then the British defeated the Sikh
Empire and took over the Sikh Empire.
And eventually when they when the
British who occupied India when they
finally decided to demarcate the India
Afghanistan boundary after the Angloik
wars, they decided to create this Duran
line along
along the the the borders of the Sikh
Empire which included a lot of Pashon
territory.
Okay. In 1947 when the British left and
divided India, partitioned India, that
became the Pakistan Afghanistan boundary
and that is the cause of a major
territorial dispute that exists even
today. Now let's once again go back
in the 20th century you had Muhammad
Dawud Khan I believe who was the
who was the cousin of the ruler of
Afghanistan. the the ruler of
Afghanistan, his name was Zahir Sha
and his cousin Muhammad Dawud Khan was
appointed by Zahir Sha as the prime
minister of Afghanistan.
Now Muhammad Dawud Sha had the choice.
See now the 20th century you have the
cold war right after the end of the
second world war you have the cold war
and Pakistan has allied itself with the
Americans and Pakistan Afghanistan have
this major territorial dispute.
So so um this guy Dawud Khan Dawud Khan
he had the choice he he had to decide
what to do. Do I also align like
Pakistan with the Americans or do I
align myself and my country with the
Soviets?
So there was a tug of war. Both the
Americans and Soviets were courting
Afghanistan. But Dawud Mohammed Daw Khan
decided to go with go with the USSR. So
the Soviets were very happy. They were
very pleased that Afghanistan is on our
side and they gave Afghanistan all kinds
of aid, all kinds of support. They uh
sold lots of military equipment, tanks,
fighter planes,
artillery, small arms, ammunition, all
that to to Afghanistan. They also the
Soviets also set up air bases in
Afghanistan. Who constructed Bagram air
base? It was the USSR who constructed
the Bagram Air Base for the for the
Afghans. They also used it. So,
so all this happens in the 1950s.
It's around the 1950s that this happens.
So, Afghanistan initially Muhammad Alhan
initially was thinking about being on
the American side. But the Americans
insisted that you to you to sign
agreements with us. You to sign a mutual
defense agreement etc. which essentially
vasalizes you. And Afghanistan did not
want to be vasalized. So they went with
the Soviets. India was also aligned with
the Soviets. Afghanistan was also
aligned with the Soviets. So the
Americans now pro the Pakistanis that
create problems for Afghanistan.
Right? So the Pakistanis start using
Islamist tactics in Afghanistan. See the
the government of Afghanistan the
Muhammad Daud Khan government was a
nationalistic government
and and a nationalistic government will
want its territory back. So Pakistan
said let's let's u you know try and do a
regime change in Afghanistan and put an
Islamist government in place so that
it's all about religion not about
territory anymore. So that makes
Pakistan and Afghanistan on the same
page. So they tried to you know prop up
you know they tried to forment troubles
in Afghanistan and there were clashes
along the Afghanistan Pakistan border
you know low-level clashes and so on. So
this continues in the 1950s60s.
Uh eventually what happens in the 1970s
is that the Pakistanis are supporting
these warlords
um
warlords such as Burhanuin Rabani
Gulbodin Hebati Ahmed Sham Masud etc.
They are supporting these warlords and
tried trying to create lots of trouble
for Afghanistan.
And then there is an attempt to do a
coup in Afghanistan. At some point in
time in the 1970s, Muhammad Dawud Khan
ousted his his his uncle Zahir Sha as
the sha as a king of Afghanistan and he
proclaimed Afghanistan as a republic.
Okay. And then there is this trouble
with Pakistan. The Pakistanis are trying
to use Islamism
um as a tool against Afghanistan. Then
there is an attempted coup in
Afghanistan in the late 1970s somewhere
probably 78 or something. Um
and Muhammad Daud Sha is able to
suppress that
but then there are protests against him
and the Islamists become very powerful
and there's a lot of instability and
Muhammad Daw Shad massacres some people
that sort of thing happens and then
and then the Soviets they had also
cultivated a a communist party in
Afghanistan which was called the
Afghanistan people's democratic party or
something and eventually they there was
a revolution in Afghanistan called the
sour revolution and you had a communist
takeover of the country by this
Afghanistan people's democratic party or
whatever Muhammad Daw Sha is uh killed
in that coup and then there is
infighting in 1978 or thereabouts
between various factions in the
communist party and the Soviets who are
very happy with this communist takeover
of Afghanistan they are trying to patch
things up but the guy who is in power
whose name I forget. He said that I will
not listen to the Soviet Union. If you
guys try to pressurize me, I will go and
go get into bed with the Americans.
Okay. So he started become becoming pro
America. And that was the last stro for
the USSR. So Leonit Brev in 1975 said
invade.
And that's how the invasion happened in
1979.
So long story short,
the Soviets wanted control over
Afghanistan. They could not afford to
have Afghanistan fall into Pakistani and
American orbits
and that's why they invaded Afghanistan.
But they they don't do a good job of it
as we know and eventually it was a
catastrophe.
So whether you can call it a just cause,
unjust cause, whatever, but that is how
it happened. Those were that was a chain
of events roughly. You can read the
details with all the dates etc. But
that's overall how it happened.
Krishna of the Surinamese Netherlands
says I understand from your explanations
about vegetarianism that it originally
originally comes from Janism and
Buddhism. Do you mean that vegetarianism
does not belong to Hinduism at all? Do I
understand that correctly? You see Hindu
what we call Hinduism is not something
that has a 500 year history. It has
maybe 10,000 years of history maybe even
more. The oldest text of what we call
Hinduism today. Today we call Hinduism.
The oldest text of that is the Rigveda
which was written thousands of years ago
at a time when the Sarasati River was in
her prime. That's when the Riga was
written. What year what is was it? We
don't know for sure. Maybe closer to
6,000 BC than to 2,000 BC because 2,000
BC the river disappears in the southern
half of its course.
um and 6,000 BC is when the decline
initially starts the decline of the
river. So the rigida was written closer
to 6,000 BC than to 2,000 BC. Now the
oldest religious text not just for
Hinduism but for the entire world. The
oldest literary text in the world
therefore is the rigida. Now that is you
could say the foundation of Hindu what
what we call Hinduism today. Eventually
you had other vedas that were written
and then you had so many tens of
thousands of texts that were written
about Hinduism which are all part of
what we now call Hinduism. So if we look
at the original text the foundational
text the oldest text the riga what does
it say about eating meat?
It says so here's here are the things it
says it says killing of cows is
unacceptable. Cows are not to be killed.
If somebody kills cow, the punishment
should be really harsh. So cows are not
to be killed. That's what the rigida
says. The rigida also says that horses
are not to be killed unless it's the
ashamed yagna. So only a great king can
do it. Otherwise horses can't be killed.
It doesn't say anything about any other
animals.
And it does prescribe various yagnas in
which animals are sacrificed and eaten.
So in the rigveda it's very clear you
don't kill cows, you don't kill horses
except if you are a great chakraarti
king and you then you can do the asha
yagna. So the rigida doesn't say a thing
about not eating meat. It only specifies
which animals are not to be killed.
That's all. So do you have any advocacy
or prescription for vegetarianism in the
rigida? None whatsoever.
Then you have aturva which comes later.
Right? In the we have lists of animals
which should not be killed. So it it
it's an expanded list. It not only has
the cow and the horse, it also has deer,
you know, wild deers and various other
animals. So it's an expanded list of of
course the rigid also says you can't
kill humans. Okay, it says you can't
kill humans unless it's war or crime or
whatever.
So in the in the yajour ve you have
other animals that can't be killed but
but once again it doesn't say that you
have a universal
prescription or mandate for being
vegetarian. Later we have all kinds of
other philosophical schools of thought
that came in right later schools of
thought and some of these become you
know advocates of vegetarianism.
So today depending on what school of
thought you follow whether you are a
Vishna whether you are a shite whether
you are this whether you are that
depending on what you follow you will
live a certain lifestyle
right so univers so Hinduism is not a
universal universalistic
way of life or religion it's not a
monolithic religion all kinds of
practices are allowed in Hinduism you
can be a pure vegetarianism or you can
be a pure vegetarian
You can be vegan if you want to. You can
eat only spaghetti if it's if if it
suits you. Spaghetti ugly olio or you
could eat carnivorous diet if you if you
like. The only thing you can't eat if
you're a Hindu which all aspects of
Hinduism agree upon is cows.
Apart from that and I'm sure also
horses. Yeah. Why would you want to eat
horses by the way? And of course um um I
don't think I would discuss dogs and
cats right over here because no Indians
would no in no civilized Indian eats
dogs or cats. Um yeah anyway so there's
no references to dogs or cats in the
atravida but there is reference to
there's a reference to a dog in the
mahabharat right because yudushir when
he finally met with lord yama yamraj
he said that I will not ascend to heaven
unless I can bring my dog with me
because he has been faithful to me all
this time I can't leave my friend friend
behind so Yamaraj had to lord Yama had
to agree to the dog join ing yudish in
the swagal loca. So that's how we know
that in our swagal loca dogs are
allowed.
So anyway that's the deal. So if you
look at the rigid there is no advocacy
there is no prescription that you can't
eat meat. None whatsoever.
And then depending on which school of
thought or school philosophical school
of thought you follow in Hinduism today
you may or you may not eat meat. But so
so it's allowed if you want to if you
are a shaka I suppose you eat meat
if you are a shite I suppose you can eat
meat if you are a vishnav no no no meat
no no no no no no no no and other other
stuff as well so it's entirely up to you
it's your choice what appeals to you
which way of life appeals to you within
Hinduism you can do whatever the only
thing is you can't eat beef
that's
Brian Seeker Biswar says, "Could you
explain the origins of the Ben Israeli
Benes Jewish community in India? How the
roots compare with those of other Jewish
groups like the Kochin Jews and Baghdadi
Jews? Is there any actual historical and
genetic study suggesting how these
distinct Jewish communities emerged and
evolved in the Indian subcontinent?"
Okay. So, the Beni Israel Jews are the
Maharashtrain Jews. They live on the
west coast of India and you know
Maharashtra region. Then you have the
Kochin Jews who are Kerala Jews and then
you have the Baghdadi Jews who came much
later. So what's the origin of the Ben
Israeli community? It is said that
around 2,100 or 2,200 years ago, a group
of Jewish people was shipwrecked on the
west coast of India
and that happened to be the Maharashtra
region, what is today the Maharashtra
region and uh seven couples survived.
Seven Jewish couples survived and they
settled down in western India in
Maharashtra and uh
their descendants are the Beni Israeli.
their roots go back about 200 2,100 or
2,200 years ago. So it it corresponds
with the Seucid Empire,
a time when the Seucid Empire had was
was
oppressing the Jews in their homeland.
Yeah. Who was it? Which was the king?
Antiocus something or whoever it was.
So yeah, that's the origin said that's
said to be the origin of the Ben Israeli
community and for 2,000 plus years they
have been in India and they have become
super Indianized. They don't even look
Israeli or Jewish. They look like
Indians but they continue to practice
certain aspects of Judaism like uh
Israeli is the prayer. So they would do
the prayer. uh they would uh do
circumcision or whatever that is certain
Jewish practices they were able to they
they were able to remember and continue
and they they they they observed Shabbat
which is they don't work on Saturday or
something whatever it is and they were
able to live in India prosper thrive and
they became super Indianized over time
and later some Jewish people who came to
India much later discovered this group
of people who are practicing in Judaism
but have be who have become Indian and
they reintroduced some other ways of
Judaism to them and that's that's a
story genetically there have been some
studies I don't have the exact studies
with me right now but that kind of those
studies do indicate that these people
have mixed ancestry significant Indian
ancestry but also ancestry from West
Asia and that ancestry dates back to
about roughly 2,000 years ago so the
Beni Israeli are indeed of West Asian
probably Jewish uh ancestry
and they have been in India for over
2,000 years and they have thrived in
India for 2,000 over 2,000 years. The
coaching Jews are said to be even older
an even older Jewish population. Um
according to their folklore they either
come from the time of king Solomon
that is about said to be about 900 BC or
maybe the time of the Babylonian exile
which is the 6th century BC or
something.
So around that time they they came to
India and they settled down in Kerala.
So they have been in India for a very
very very long time. And about
about 500 or so years ago there was the
expulsion of the um of the Iberian Jews
from Spain as part of the aftermath of
the reconista which happened in 1492 or
thereabouts. You can look up the dates
reconista.
And in the aftermath of the reconista of
Spain, expulsion of the Islamic Mo from
Spain, the Jews were also expelled, the
Sepharim. And a bunch of these Jews,
Safharim Jews, Sepharic Jews, they came
and settled down in Kerala and
intermingled with the Cochin Jews. And
they called the Cochin Jews black Jews
because they had become Indian. And the
Sepharin were white whitish.
So they mixed with the uh intermingled
with the coaching Jews. Today's coaching
Jews are a descendant of those two
communities. The old ancient
um community from um from probably
during the Babylonian exile time but
definitely before the Roman destruction
of the second temple
and the sepharen who came about what the
16th century AD. So that's the Kochin
Jews. The Baghdadi Jews are a very
recent Jews entrance into India. um what
17th 18th centuries around that time the
Baghdadi Jews came to India. They
settled down in western India. The first
place they settled down was probably
Surat in West India, western India,
Gujarat, southern Gujarat, then Mumbai
which was then called Bombay and one of
the most prominent of the Baghdadi
Jewish families was the Sassoons. So the
Baghdadi Jews came from West Asia from
uh the Iraq region, Baghdad, Basarak
also Syria, Aleppo etc. and they
did not intermix that much with the
Indians. They remained separate and
distinct and the Fasoons became like I
said a very prominent uh industrialized
industrial family, a business family,
very very wealthy. They were called the
Roshells of the east or something. Okay.
and they were they were into various
enterprises. Um you have the Sassoon
docks in Mumbai which is named after the
Cassoons. You have the Cassoon library
also in Mumbai and the Cassoons are al
they also made their presence felt in
China in Shanghai. In 19th century China
the Cassoons played a significant role
in what the Chinese call the century of
humiliation beginning with the opium
wars. The Cassoons were
prominent traders of opium and so on. So
anyhow these are the distant distinct
Jewish communities that emerged and
evolved in the subcontinent. When it
comes to the Baghdadi sorry the
Benisraeli and the Kochin Jews there is
genetic evidence that corroborates those
those uh folk that that folklore that
they have about themselves that kind of
corroorates what they have said. Um and
the the the the Baghdadi Jews hardly
exist in India at all anymore. I don't
think any of them exist today. But uh
the BI is some of them do exist. The
coin some of them still exist in India.
Um most of the Jewish people have done
aliyah. They have gone and settled down
in Israel and set up cricket clubs over
there. Some still live in India. And
India is one place that has welcomed the
Jews with open arms and treated them the
same as Indians. And the Jews have
prospered in India. Not a single
instance of anti-semitism ever against
Jews has occurred in India. The
Europeans, the way they've treated Jews
for 2,000 years. All kinds of horrific
accusations against the Jews. Blood liel
and what uh
I don't know the poisoning of wealths
allegedly. All that nonsense. If the
Jews are so evil and so on like the
Europeans have claimed for 2,000 years.
How did how come the Jews never did such
any such thing in India? So clearly the
Europeans have been lying for 2,000
years. No question about it.
Interesting, isn't it?
Right.
Rishi says, "Why does Wikipedia
propagate the lie that Brahmic scripts
come from the from Egyptian heroglyphics
when it's obvious that Brahmic scripts
originated in India?" Let's find out
what Wikipedia is saying. As I always
say, Wikipedia is not
necessarily a reliable source of
information. It lies about India. Okay,
let's see. Brah, no, sorry. Brahmic
scripts. All right. What does Wikipedia
say about this Wikipedia?
Um, go on, bro. Okay, they are descended
from the Brahi script. Let's go to what
it says about Brahiscript. It says the
Brahmos scripts it originates in the
Aramaic alphabet which comes from the
Phoenician alphabet eventually from the
Egyptian heroglyphs. So that's what it
claims. The origin of the script is
still debated but most scholars state
that Brahmy was derived from or
influenced by semiotic scripts,
contemporary sematic scripts. U some
scholars favor the idea of an indigenous
origin but the evidence is insufficient
at best. But there is apparently
evidence that it came it comes from
Aramaic and eventually Egyptian
heroglyphs. Interesting, isn't it? Now,
now let's go back to Google and see what
our friend Groipedia has to say about
this. Elon Musk's neutral
version of Wikipedia. Let's see what it
has to say. Okay. Brahmei script
Groipedia.
Groipedia. What's it say? Okay,
Grochipedia. Let's go to Grocipedia.
It's going to be dark screen. Dark dark.
Yeah, here. Here we have it. The
braiscript is an ancient abigura writing
system. Blah blah blah blah blah.
Evidence suggesting it was a deliberate
invention or adaptation.
Its development reflects encloses from
sematic scripts like Aramaic
introduced through trade or
administrative conducts but restructured
into an indigenous alphabetical order
bas based on vicology.
So even Groipedia, Elon Musk's allegedly
neutral
version of Wikipedia or neutral um
encyclopedia says that Brahmy has come
from the Sematic scripts, Aramaic
eventually Egyptian herographs. Absolute
nonsense. The Brahi script has come from
the Indus, the so-called Indascript, the
Saraswati script, the Indus Sarasati
script, the Hindu Saras script.
No question about it. which has been
recently deciphered by Barat Rao also
known as Yajjan Devam and you can watch
my conversation with him on this very
channel.
Okay,
he has deciphered the um Sarasati Sindu
script, Indascript, whatever you want to
call it and the Brahi script is clearly
derived from the Indascript. No question
about it. So Wikipedia, Grochipedia, all
these encyclopedia, Britannica, they're
they all have this euroentric
perspective which seeks to minimize
everything that India has done and
that's that's why we have this
situation.
No surprise there.
Suhin Reyes says at the time of
independence in 1947, why did our
leaders not show any interest in merging
neighbors like Nepal, Sri Lanka,
Myanmar, Bhutan into India?
You know there's this uh apocryphal
story about Stalin right when the Indian
ambassador to the USSR met with Stalin
um Stalin was shown a map of the Indian
subcontinent with India Pakistan blah
blah blah all that and Stalin points to
this island he says what is this island
south of India and the Indian ambassador
proudly says this is the independent
nation of Sri Lanka and Stalin looks at
looks at the person with disbelief and
says why is that an independent nation
why What is wrong with you people? So at
the time of independence 1947, our
leaders clearly did not show any
interest in merging neighbors like
Nepal, Sri Lanka, Myanmar, Bhutan into
India. On the contrary,
they were very willing to help the
British in balconizing India.
They created East and West Pakistan out
of India out of our territory, the
territory that our ancestors lived in.
Right? They our our our so-called
leaders were willing to create this very
thin chicken neck which connected our
far east with the mainland and put east
Pakistan in the middle and today we
still have the same problem. We gave up
Pakistan. We gave up gave up parts of
Kashmir. We gave up Axai. Our leaders
were not interested in in in merging new
territories into India or old ter or or
or reabsorbing old old territories. They
were happy to allow India to be
fragmented and bulcanized further.
The Sultan of Oman offered guada to
India. We refused.
The Khan of Kalat in Balojasthan wanted
to merge with India. We refused.
The Maharaja of Kashmir had to request
Mr. Nu three times by sending the
instrument of accession three times to
Mr. Neu and NU refused. It was Mount
Batton who finally accepted. There are
so many stories. We gave up the Kabo
Valley which was historically part of
Manipur, the kingdom of Manipur. We gave
up to gave it up to Burma. We gave up
the Koko Islands to Burma as a gift. He
has a gift for as it belongs to me,
right? So I I'll give it up. That's the
kind of leaders we had. Why? I have no
idea. I I don't I don't know what they
were thinking. What the great
magnificent man was thinking. I have no
idea why.
Beats me. Okay.
All right. Multiple questions about the
same topic. Really? now says when
exactly did the Europeans start
significant intellectual theft from
India they had no inventions and
discoveries for a forever essentially
and then suddenly there was this barrage
of new theorems and concepts this period
also seems to coincide with India's
decline under successful invasions and
the beginning of Turk colonialism
perplexity refuses to admit that Kepler
or Newton got any knowledge from India
no intellectual theft happened and these
people only built upon what their
European predecessors like Taikobra
Calleo
uh and Copernicus originally came up
with infuriating all major physics laws
formulated by Europeans like Kepler,
Newton, Galileo's discoveries of sudden
rings etc all seemed to be from the
1600s. Suddenly everything starts starts
in the 1600s right after Jesuits visited
India and European colonial colonialism
was taking root. Is it a coincidence?
Also these extractions are called are
being called rumors by chat bots like
what perplexity I'm sure chat jpd and
whoever else right all these chatbots so
what's the deal how did this all begin
it all begins with the destruction of
India's universities and libraries India
was the inventor of the concept of the
university the oldest university that we
know of is Takashila which uh has its
origins in the first around the around
the mid first millennium BC
And we had universities across the
length and the breadth of India. Naland
Takshila, Tilhara, Udantaapuri, Vikram
Shila, Shardir and so on and so forth,
so on and so forth. So many. So we have
the universities all over the place. Now
you have the Turks who eventually start
conquering various parts of India. And
whenever they see a temple, they destroy
it. They plunder all the golden jewels,
Jews and all that. And wherever they see
universities, initially the Turks sent
interpreters and uh scholars okay to
India and they would visit our
universities to they would visit the
libraries and they would take all the
texts that they found interesting. So if
it was a text about Hindu philosophy,
they didn't care about it. But it was if
it was a text about mathematics, about
astronomy, about pharmarmacology, about
toxicology, about uh science, about
medicine
etc. All these applied subjects they
wanted that un that knowledge. So these
al-qarismi and al- bironi etc. They all
came to India. They took whatever they
could, all the texts they could and they
studiously, religiously translated all
these texts from Sanskrit into either
Persian or Arabic. And the Arabs who did
this,
they did not conceal the fact that this
was Indian knowledge. Alarism says he
what what did he title his book
alabhind?
Let's Google it, shall we? Am I making
this up?
Am I making this up? Let's see. Okay.
Kab alhab al hind.
What was this?
It's a book by the Persian mathematician
alisme
which translated the Indian decimal
positional system to Arabic al-hab right
the principles of Hindu reckoning.
So that's by Alarismi.
Um no this is uh okay this isabi ushab
al-hind it's a different book it's a
book of mathematics written by kushar
ibn laban
and you have all these different Arabic
um Arabic and Persian translators
who translate all these Indian texts
into their languages and they don't
claim that they invented or discovered
any of this but today al-Qism albei are
regarded by the dressed as polymats as
if they came up with all these concepts
on their own. They never claimed that
this was their
you know this is knowledge that they
came up with they were simply
translators but today the westerners
portray Alqarismi and Alberun etc as the
independent discoverers of all these
things
so that's where the the distortion
begins
and then you had this Jesuits who would
come to India so so what happened is
that the Arabs and the Persians that
took all of this knowledge from India
eventually the the occupier the Turk
occupars of India destroyed all the
universities and burn burnt all the
libraries. But all the interesting texts
were taken and absorbed into the and
translated into Islamic languages um
Persian and Arabic. And all of this
knowledge that flowed into the Islamic
world, it gave rise to what they call
the golden age of Islam. Two three
centuries of of liberal thought in Islam
of a flowering of knowledge. You had the
great library of Baghdad and you know uh
the Islamic Golden Age which was brought
to a sudden abrupt end by the by the um
by the conquest of the Arabic world of
the Islamic world by Shri Huligu Khan
the grandson of Shri Changis Khan.
The he almost destroyed the Islamic
world and that was the end of the
Islamic golden age. By that time
these translations of Hindu texts of of
Indian texts were beginning to trickle
into Europe and that's why the Europeans
decided that this was all all Arabic
stuff and even when the Europeans knew
that the Arabs Arabs had translated
Sanskrit texts they still decided to as
to ascribe all this knowledge to the
Arabs and they started claiming that
Alberun et were polymats. Then 15th 16th
century onwards the Jesuits
who are the world's greatest thieves of
knowledge they started coming to India.
They started interacting with Brahmans
in various parts of India and collecting
astronomical and other data carrying it
to to Europe going to Kerala
discovering calculus carrying it to
Europe and suddenly in the same year
both Newton and Libnitz discover
calculus. same year for 10,000 years
Europe did not know what mathematics was
suddenly the same year within a couple
of months of each each other few months
of each other both lienitz who was in
Germany and Newton who was in on on an
island in the Atlantic both of them
independently discovered calculus what a
goddamn joke so the Europeans
absorbed as much knowledge as they could
most likely um Kepler
um who was a student of thyobra if I'm
not mistaken. So Kepler most likely got
all this astronomical data from India
from through Jesuit priests and based on
all these centuries of astronomical
observations he was able to derive what
he called what is now called Kepler's
three laws of planetary motion most
likely these were these laws were known
in India but our historians won't bother
to to research this and put it out in
the public domain so that's the deal so
all of this Indian knowledge scientific
knowledge was absorbed by the west and
today they portray it as something that
either the Arabs have discovered or that
they came up with on their own and
that's the deal.
Okay.
Shub says was Zoroastronism a rebellion
against Hinduism? Well, so what's the
origin of Zoroastrinism? When did it
appear or arrive? See, it is said that
Kurush,
King Kurush, Emperor Kurush, Cyrus the
Great, Kurush of Vazarak, it is said
that he was not Zoroastpri. So it is
said that Zorashinism came after Kurush.
So Kurush when did he rule? He was one
of the great kings of the Aminid empire
dynasty. Uh Cyrus
the great
the Jews are fond of him because he was
benevolent towards them. He freed them.
So so obviously the sixth centuryish
BCish. Yeah. sixth sixth sixth
sixthish century BC that's Cyrus and
most likely he was not Zoroastrian
which means he followed the
pre-zoroastrian religion of Persia what
was that
we'll not go into it again it was
Hinduism
paganism it was a form of paganism what
Hinduism okay so Cyrus was most likely
Hindu but then you have the emergence of
prophet Zarat
And uh suddenly Zoroastrianism becomes
the state religion some point in time.
What was the shape and form of
Zoroastrianism? So it says that there is
the central great god not angra not
angramanu but ahuramazda. Angramanu is
the bad guy. So ahuram mazda is the good
guy. He's the great benevolent god. Then
you have other divinities
also in zoroastronism. You will be told
that Zoroastrianism is monotheistic
which is a li which is a lie. Let me
show you various Zoroastrian gods. Have
you heard of Vitrahan?
Let's see.
Have you heard of Vitraa?
Vitraa
is a Zoroastrian Yazat or deity
divinity. Okay.
Vitraa means he who defeated or
destroyed Vitra.
Who was Vitra? He was the great serpent
who encircled the oceans of the world.
And who defe who who defeated Vitra? It
was Indra, Lord Indra, who defeated
Vitra. Vitrahan in Sanskrit means the
slayer of Vitra which means Indra.
And Vitra Vitra is one of the deities in
Zoroastrianism. So Indra is a
Zoroastrian deity. We also have myth.
See in in Roman religion we have the
mitriic mysteries.
The mithriic mysteries. Okay. What is
this? A Roman cult mystery religion
focused on the god Mitras. This is the
worship of the Zoroastrian divinity
Mitra. Once again a Zoroastrian god. Who
is the Zoroastrian god Mitra? It is some
nothing but Mitra. The Vic god Mitra.
Mitrauna. Right. Mr and Vun come
together.
So, Zoroastrinism is
polytheistic. It is you could say an
offshoot of Hinduism. All the major
Hindu divinities are part of the
Zoroastran pantheon. But at the top you
have some you have the great god Ahur
Mazda which probably is an invention of
Zoroastra of Zeratustra and you also
have the bad guy which is uh Angramano.
So it is a is it a rebellion against
Hinduism? I think it is nothing very
much different from what Goautam Buddha
did. He also took dharma into a certain
different direction and he yeah so he
established his own school of thought
which was different from the mainstream
school of thought and similarly
zoroastra zaratustra also did something
similar and he also termed he inverted
the the terminology so that so the
assuras or ahuras become the good guys
and the das become the bad guys in
zoroastrinism
and in the vic religion it's the other
way around the assuras aren't really bad
guys in the Vic religion but they are
kind of complex
divinities aren't there so that's what
Zoroastinism was not quite a rebellion
against Hinduism but you could say
perhaps Zaratustra was a social reformer
or something and he wanted to change
some aspects of Hinduism so they came up
with this thing and which is now and
obviously you have the worship of Agni
Agni right they have these fires that
have been going on for centuries
thousands of years. So they worship
Agni. So not quite a rebellion of Hindu
against Hinduism but kind of a
reformation, an attempt to reform
Hinduism in certain ways. That's what
Zoroastrianism
was.
Okay, we have crossed two hours but I
still have some questions. What do I do?
Let's take Okay, let's take one question
more. This is by Saloni Mishra. Why did
the Roman Empire not focus on conquering
the entirety of Europe instead of going
to Africa and Asia?
Right? Okay. See, when you conquer a
territory, it's a big undertaking. You
have to set aside a certain number of
soldiers, maybe 10,000, maybe 20,000
soldiers. You have to send them
to capture a territory that is not
yours, which means you have to fight a
war.
To fight a war, you have to supply them
with whatever they need. Arms,
ammunition, new weapons. Some of them
will die. So you have to resupply them
and send more soldiers. Perhaps you have
to ensure that they are they have
sufficient food supplies. Takes a lot of
effort, lot of money. It empties your
treasury.
So then the question is
which territories should should you
conquer? Should you conquer all
territories or should you conquer those
territories from which you will get more
money than you spend?
See Europe if you look at places like
Ukraine tremendous fertile land. Ukraine
also existed during Roman times. Makes
sense to conquer it. If you look at Gaul
which is France and Switzerland very
fertile lands and lots of people there
you can either use them as slaves or you
can use the the land for agriculture and
you will get revenue from that. If you
conquer Spain, there is gold there.
Right? So, wherever you have territories
with lots of people,
if you conquer those territories, you
will get a lot of revenue from there. If
you go north of the river Rin or go east
of the river Danube, you will find these
forested territories, super cold
territories, sparsely populated
territories like Gmana, Gmana Magna,
and the Nordic territories like what is
now Sweden, Norway, etc. super cold,
super frozen, sparsely populated, no
agricultural agriculture possible there,
no source of revenue. You go and capture
that and then what will you do? You had
to station soldiers there, lots of
soldiers and you have to pay for that.
What sense does it make? But if you
conquer let's say Egypt, big population
there and you can extract revenue from
that. If you conquer North Africa, big
population centers established there for
centuries. You can tax them. You can
force them to pay tribute.
They can go and do all the dirty work in
the Sahil region or wherever and they'll
have they have to pay you a yearly
tribute. So why not capture those
territories, right? So so that's why it
doesn't make economic sense to capture
everything only capture the rich
prosperous regions from which there is
guaranteed tribute which will come in
every year or guaranteed resources that
will come in every year. That's what
makes sense to capture. That's why the
Roman Empire did not waste its energy,
resources, men, manpower, whatever in
capturing the whole of Europe because
the whole of Europe was not valuable. It
captured all the valuable territories.
It went as far east as possible. It c
captured Judea, which is presently
Israel, the Israel region, West Asia
region, but it could no not go further,
further east because it ran into the
Persian Empire. The Persians captured a
Roman emperor
and humiliated him. What was his name?
Let's find out. Okay.
Which Persian emperor, which Roman
emperor,
Roman emperor
did Persia?
Persia capture. Okay. Which Roman? Yeah.
Here we have Valyrian. The Roman emperor
captured by the Persians was Valyrian
who was defeated and captured by Shapur
the first in 260 AD.
This is one of the most significant
humiliations in Roman history. Okay. So
the Romans understood we better not
fight Persia. What's the point? We have
enough territory. We will that will give
us enough wealth. So that's why the
Roman Empire went as far as it could go.
Did not go where it was too difficult to
fight. When you had a too powerful of an
empire like the Persians did not go too
far north because that land was useless.
You would not get any significant
revenue from that and you would have to
spend more than you got out of it. So
these are the reasons why the Roman
Empire did not focus on cap on capturing
all of the on conquering the entirety of
Europe. It instead went in other
directions like North Africa and West
Asia. Okay. Okay. That should bring me
to the end of today's live stream. I
still have more questions that I've
selected but yeah we have we have almost
reached two hours 20 minutes. So let me
take a few questions
from the live. Jan as as always I can
see that there are a few super chats.
Please stop taking super chats. I'll
deal with these that we have. And uh
yeah, so Danam Priya Priyad is a new
member. Thank you so much. Dwanam Priya
Priy, welcome to membership. I really
appreciate it. I never ever asked anyone
to become a member, but you're still
doing it many of you. So thank you so
much to you sir or ma'am. I think it's
sir. It's a male name Priya. Thank you.
Thank you to you and to everyone else
who has become a member. Thank you so
much. Now, Godliness says, "Explain the
history of museums. When did museums
come into existence and what was kept in
the early museums and do you want to
visit any historical museum?" Okay,
there. Okay, I forget her name. I forget
her name. Um I'm not sure about the
history of museums in Batwash in the
subcontinent but there was this this
Mesopotamian
princess who was the first curator who
maintained the first museum. I forget
these Mesopotamian names are very hard
to remember. So a Mesopotamian princess
Mesopotamian
princess
uh museum
okay f first museum let's let's ah
first museum okay her name was Inigi
Nana
Inigal Nana Princess Inigal Nana uh she
established a museum around 560 60 BC in
the city of Ur in modern day Iraq
and she cured a collection of artifacts
from previous eras of Mesopotamian
history and these were labeled in
multiple languages for visitors.
Okay, so incredible. So this this
princess from about 500 something BC,
Princess Inaldina,
daughter of King Nabidus, which is
clearly a Greek version of the actual
name.
So she was the first known uh museum
curator or the first known person who
established a museum. Uh that's what I
can tell you apart from that history of
museums. That will be a 2hour long
3-hour long discussion but that's an
interesting historical fact. It's a
Mesopotamian princess who established
the first known museum. There may be
older ones but this is the first one the
oldest one we know of. Okay. and
artifacts from previous civil previous
empires, kingdom civilizations were kept
in her museums.
Uh, do I want to visit any historical
museums? I would love to. I would. Yeah.
When I was in London, I did not go to
the British Museum, right? Yeah, I did
not. I spent my time at the Tower of
London.
Uh, anyway, so yeah, I would love to
visit the British Museum and and
take a look at our stolen heritage over
there. And uh yeah, museums are fun to
visit. I don't mind visiting all
museums. Visiting Indian museums is is
is kind of a depressing proposition
because of the terrible way in which our
uh heritage is is uh preserved and
displayed there. Terrible, terrible,
shameful. There's not a single
world-class museum in this country in
India. Anyway, okay. Next. UMX says,
"Has how Scandinavia became so rich
historically poor?"
How did Scandinavia become so rich?
It was part of Europe and um it's a
welfare state kind of.
How has Scandinavia become so rich? I'm
not sure I can quite answer the question
right now. That would involve a lot of
different historical tangents that all
come together in one place. Lots of
different wars they fought with the
Russians and the Germans and so on. Long
long long long answer I will need
won't be able to answer it now but good
question maybe I'll take it up at some
other point in time okay not sonatan
says okay did India price continuity or
conquest did India price continuity or
conquest India prized conquest whenever
it was required um
for example India see Indian kings
historically wanted conquest up to the
subcontinent they did not want to cross
the Himalayas. Too cold up there north
of the Himalayas. uh they do not want to
cross into central Asia because once you
cross the kyber what is now called the
kyber pass you're in a totally different
zone or region of the world and uh
and the subcontinent was
so valuable
I mean so resourcerich
that conquering other parts like central
Asia made no sense whatsoever economic
sense whatsoever unless you was you were
kaneshka in which case you knew how to
play the him.
So um Indian emperors, rulers prized the
subcontinent. They would they all sought
to conquer the subcontinent. Some of
them did like Ashok did. Kaneshkar was a
hybrid conqueror. He conquered very
large parts of Central Asia including uh
the shores of the as Caspian and Aral
seas and also parts of what is now
China, Shinjang, the Shinjang region,
Tibet region and much of northern and
western India all the way to the west
coast.
And then you have uh the Gupta emperors.
Some of them went into central Asia,
Bahalik that region.
And then we have the Cholas who
conquered the whole of Southeast Asia.
So each empire is different but yeah
continuity the civilization has
continued but dynasties have come and
gone.
What are my views says Anand Pancharan
Rajar Ra Mahanro is a social reformer.
Why does India need social reform? Why
why doesn't Europe We don't have social
reformers in Europe right who are trying
to reform European society. You don't
have social reformers in in in in in in
China who are trying to reform Chinese
society. You don't have social reformers
in the United States who are trying to
reform US society. We only have these
social reformers in Indian society
somehow. And somehow they all have ties
to the occupiers and colonizers somehow.
Yeah. So my
view on this gentleman Mr. Ram Muanroy
is very clear. He was an agent of the
occupiers and he was an enemy of our
civilization. Very clear about that. And
I've spoken about this in detail in in
the past. If you do a simple search on
my channel about Ram Moy, I have a I
have at least one video clip about this
in which I've spoken about this.
Okay. Gapati says, "Was the Look, we're
discussing history today, sir. History.
We're discussing history. We're not
discussing current affairs in
geopolitics.
I request you all please take a look at
the title of this YouTube live stream.
It's world and Indian history.
So let's not discuss other topics today
otherwise it becomes a free-for-all or
free for all. You need to value
discipline in life sometimes
not sometimes always.
So I'm going to stick to my discipline.
Today is a history episode. I will not
take this. I really apologize that you
have spent money on this but please
understand this is a history live
stream. All right. Thank you.
Jazz 1993 says please talk about
Uttarakhan history. I'm from Uttar.
Nobody talks about it.
I don't know much about Uttarakhan
history. I'm very sorry. I don't know.
Uttarakhand is this beautiful part
of the subcontinent. Beautiful place.
But I am not familiar with the history
of Utarakand.
So I don't know what to say. I don't
know. I don't know in detail any about
the history of Utakand. First of all,
it's not it's not a very large part of
India, right? It's a comparatively you
could say smaller region of India. A
very interesting geographical region
location. Himalayan foothills.
Very interesting
culture.
very interesting u
manifestations of Hinduism and dharma in
the place but the history I am not
really well aware of so I won't be able
to I'm very sorry I apologize for that
but I I thank you for the question and
it's a wonderful place I can tell you
that all right I think that brings us to
the end of today's live stream almost
two and a half hours
And uh
yep.
Okay. So, let me end the live stream
right here.
I'm just watching the comments and
people are making fun of 200 rupees
wasted.
You know what? I don't like negativity.
I don't appreciate that. Please don't
make fun of people in that way. Please
don't gloat when somebody spend money
and they did not get what they wanted
out of it. What's the point of gloating?
Do you enjoy someone's misfortune?
Why do you enjoy someone's misfortune? I
don't get it. Anyway, I'm not here to
lecture you all. You live your life
whichever way you want. It's up to you
your life. But anyway, thank you
everybody for the questions
and I look forward to seeing you
tomorrow in tomorrow's live stream which
will be a freeforall. Ask me anything.
All right. Ask me any question tomorrow.
It's going to be a um it's going to be a
super chat live stream and not just
geopolitics but everybody else. Saga, no
problem. It's okay, Saga. No issues. No
issues.
No issues. Please, please be more
positive, sir. Saga, please be more
positive. Everybody, let's be more
positive. Let's be more
bring more positivity to the world.
Okay, no problem. No issues. I'll see
you all tomorrow. Please raise your
standards in instead of lowering your
standards. Take care everyone. I'll see
you tomorrow. Bye-bye. Take care.